<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<articles><article><title>Jogulamba Gadwal: Six Sentenced to Life Imprisonment in Murder Case</title><authors>Dc Correspondent, About The Author</authors><publish_date>2024-11-28</publish_date><text>Jogulamba Gadwal: The Principal District and Sessions Court in Mahabubnagar sentenced six persons to life imprisonment and imposed a fine of Rs. 3,500 each in connection with the 2016 murder of former village sarpanch Pani Kurumanna in Manopad.

The murder fueled by an ongoing feud since 2012, occurred when Kurumanna was attacked with hunting knives while on Potula Padu Road. The victim’s family alleged the crime was motivated by his role in leading witnesses in a related murder case involving the same accused.

The Manopad police under the guidance of CI P. Venkateshwarlu and SI Bhagwant Reddy conducted the investigation filing a charge sheet that led to the convictions. District SP Shri T. Srinivasa Rao IPS commended the police and legal team for ensuring justice. The convicted include Varikuntla Prasad, Varikuntla Ramanjaneyulu, Varikuntla Prakash, Varikuntla Ganga Raju, Varikuntla Garka Raju and Varikuntla Praveen.</text><top_image>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2024/11/28/1867259-hyderabad.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/jogulamba-gadwal-six-sentenced-to-life-imprisonment-in-murder-case-1842019</link></article><article><title>Constitution Day and National Law Day Celebrated with Enthusiasm at Gadwal PG Center</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-11-27</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Constitution Day, Samvidhan Divas, and National Law Day were celebrated with grandeur today at the PG Center in Nadi Agraharam, Gadwal. The event was graced by Chief Guest and Secretary of the Legal Services Authority, Senior Civil Judge Smt. Ghanta Kavitha Devi. Addressing the gathering, she emphasized that the Indian Constitution is superior to all religious texts and highlighted how it ensures the rights and freedoms of individuals. She also urged everyone to grow tulsi plants in the Tulsi Vanam (sacred grove) and to lead disciplined lives. Special mention was made about the need for women to progress in all fields.

Presiding over the event, Principal Dr. Chavva Venkat Reddy spoke about the values enshrined in the Constitution, such as liberty, equality, and fraternity, encouraging students to achieve their life goals while upholding these principles.

The program also featured remarks from Chief Legal Aid Defense Counsel Mr. Rajender and Deputy Legal Aid Defense Counsel Mr. Srinivasulu, who highlighted the importance of legal rights and awareness.

Senior faculty members, including Aravind, Dr. Mangalgiri Srinivasulu, Dr. Gopinath Rathod, Dr. Mahender, Ganesh, Mohammed Rafi, Naresh, Naveen Goud, Ghattayya, Anjaneyulu, and Lakshmaiah, actively participated in the event alongside a large number of students.

The celebration was a significant step in spreading awareness about the Indian Constitution and its values among the youth.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/11/27/1500775-pg.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/constitution-day-and-national-law-day-celebrated-with-enthusiasm-at-gadwal-pg-center-924837</link></article><article><title>Gadwal BRS MLA somersaults again!</title><authors /><publish_date /><text>A couple of days after announcing that he was returning to the Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS), Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy on Thursday changed his mind and did a somersault again into the Congress.

State excise minister Jupally Krishna Rao went to the residence of Krishna Mohan Reddy in the morning along with other MLAs in the district and convinced him to stay back in the Congress.

Apparently, Jupally conveyed the message of chief minister A Revanth Reddy that the party and the government will take care of all the political and personal interests of Krishna Mohan Reddy, if he doesn’t return to the BRS.

Later, Krishna Mohan Reddy attended the press conference along with Jupally and others. The minister told the reporters that the Gadwal MLA had met the BRS leaders in the assembly lobbies only out of his old acquaintances, but not joined the BRS.

He said Krishna Mohan Reddy would remain with the Congress and not join any other party, including the BRS.

It was only on Tuesday that the Gadwal MLA met with BRS Working President K Taraka Rama Rao and other leaders at the BRS Legislature Party office on the assembly premises and expressed his desire to rejoin the party.

He had joined the Congress party on July 6 in the presence of Chief Minister and TPCC President A Revanth Reddy and other leaders. However, he was reportedly unhappy with the party and regretted his decision.

During his meeting with KTR, Krishna Mohan Reddy requested permission for "Ghar Wapasi" (homecoming), which was accepted.

BRS leaders expressed hope that a majority of the nine other MLAs who had switched loyalties to the ruling Congress would also return to the BRS fold.

Krishna Mohan Reddy was part of a group of former BRS MLAs who made the switch, including Kale Yadaiah (Chevella), Pocharam Srinivas Reddy (Banswada), Sanjay Kumar (Jagtial), Danam Nagendra (Khairatabad), Kadiyan Srihari (Station Ghanpur), and Tellam Venkat Rao (Bhadrachalam).</text><top_image>https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/krishnamohanreddy1722498613.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/telangana-news/gadwal-brs-mla-somersaults-again-139562</link></article><article><title>After four weeks in Congress, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy returns to BRS</title><authors>Authors</authors><publish_date>2024-07-30</publish_date><text>In a political development that may hinder the ‘defections’ into the ruling party for some time, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy, who joined the Congress four weeks ago, is set to return to Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS).

Mr. Reddy met BRS working president K.T. Rama Rao (KTR) at the BRS Legislature Party (BRSLP) office in the Assembly building on Tuesday and expressed his desire to continue in the party as officially he is still recognised as a BRS member.

He was the seventh MLA from the party to have joined Congress, on July 6, 2024. Of the 10 BRS MLAs who joined the Congress, Mr. Reddy is the first one to return to parent party. The Gadwal MLA is considered to be close to KTR.

The reasons

The reasons, he quoted to the BRS leaders, were pressure from the family that was unhappy with switching sides and also opposition from the local Congress cadre, who were not welcoming him. KTR is reported to have asked him to meet BRS chief K. Chandrashekhar Rao soon.

Bhadrachalam MLA creates discomfort

Bhadrachalam MLA Tellam Venkat Rao, elected on the BRS ticket and joined the Congress later, also created some discomfort among the Congress party as he walked into the BRSLP office on Tuesday along with Balkonda MLA and former minister Prashanth Reddy. He spent some time in the office along with the BRS MLAs before going to the Assembly.

However, he has not clarified whether he will be returning to the BRS. Sources close to him said he has joined the Congress and he would continue to remain there. Mr. Venkat Rao, a close follower of Minister for Revenue Ponguleti Srinivas Reddy had joined the Congress along with him before the elections.

But he returned to the BRS again just before the Assembly elections secured the BRS party ticket from Bhadrachalam and won. He joined the Congress soon after the elections. The meeting of two MLAs with the BRS leaders created some confusion and also some tension among the Congress circles.

Will not allow the return of a few MLAs

A senior BRS leader told The Hindu that the party would not welcome back some BRS MLAs even if they wished to. He was referring to some senior MLAs who walked out of the party despite getting plum posts during the two terms of the BRS. “It is not like we will open the gates easily to those who want to return,” he said.

A blow to CM Revanth

BRS leaders also feel that Gadwal MLA coming back to the party was a blow to Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy as he was personally monitoring the joinings of BRS MLAs. “This move will push some fence-sitters into second thoughts of leaving the BRS. What confidence will we have in the Congress if an MLA is returning to the BRS,” he questioned.

He was the seventh MLA from the party to have joined Congress, on July 6, 2024. Of the 10 BRS MLAs who joined Congress, Mr. Reddy is the first one to return to the parent party. The Gadwal MLA is considered to be close to KTR</text><top_image>https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/cities/Hyderabad/w0rq6k/article68463896.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Gadwal%20MLA%20Bandal%20Krishnamohan%20Reddy%20returns%20to%20BRS.png</top_image><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/gadwal-mla-bandla-krishnamohan-reddy-returns-to-brs-after-4-weeks-in-congress/article68463915.ece</link></article><article><title>Gas Cylinder Subsidy Issues: Residents Urged to Ask Revanth Reddy for Answers</title><authors>Safiya Begum</authors><publish_date>2024-11-26</publish_date><text>Telangana: Tensions erupted in Ayiz, a town in Gadwal district, when locals confronted staff at the Shri Lakshmi Narasimha Gas Agency regarding the delayed subsidy payments for gas cylinders. The residents complained that the promised subsidy of Rs. 500 on LPG cylinders had not been credited to their accounts, causing frustration and inconvenience.

When the customers raised the issue with the agency staff, they were reportedly told to take the matter up with Revanth Reddy, the Member of Parliament (MP) from the area. According to sources, the gas agency staff deflected the blame, suggesting that the residents go and speak to Reddy if they had concerns about the subsidy payments.

This response did not sit well with the locals, who were expecting the subsidy as promised under the government’s welfare scheme. The residents questioned the accountability of local authorities in ensuring that subsidies reach the people without delay.

In Ayiz, Gadwal district, locals raised concerns over delayed Rs. 500 LPG cylinder subsidies. When they confronted the Shri Lakshmi Narasimha Gas Agency staff, they were told, "Go and ask Revanth Reddy" for answers. pic.twitter.com/uRuLyQP4HT — The Munsif Digital (@munsifdigital) November 26, 2024

The incident highlights ongoing concerns regarding the efficient delivery of government schemes in rural areas, with residents urging more transparency and quicker action to resolve such issues. The situation has led to growing discontent among the beneficiaries who feel they are being passed between various authorities without clear resolutions.

As the issue continues to unfold, locals are waiting for a response from both the gas agency and their elected representatives to ensure that the gas cylinder subsidies are processed without further delays.</text><top_image>https://2c31032a.delivery.rocketcdn.me/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/GAS-AGENCY.jpg</top_image><link>https://munsifdaily.com/gas-cylinder-subsidy-issues-residents-urged-to-ask-revanth-reddy-for-answers/</link></article><article><title>Prajavani to Solve People's Problems: GHMC Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi</title><authors>Bizz Buzz</authors><publish_date>2024-11-11</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: GHMC Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi today said prajavani programme was aimed at solving the problems of the people. The Mayor directed the concerned officials to take the initiative to look into the complaints received in the public domain and resolve them immediately.



The Mayor and the Deputy Mayor Mote Srilatha Sobhan Reddy along with the people from all over the city received grievances for the prajavani held at the GHMC headquarters on Monday. The complaints were handed over to the concerned authorities and the issues were ordered to be resolved.

Speaking on the occasion, Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi directed the officials to resolve the complaints received in the public domain from time to time without any delay. The petitioners were told that any problem should be brought to their notice and efforts would be made to resolve the issue by her. She also suggested that the right way to resolve the issues should be found and added that the petitioners should not be turned around the office and steps would be taken to resolve the grievances of the petitioners at the earliest. The petitioners have been asked to exercise restraint by her.

Four requests were received through the phone-in programme and were sent to the concerned authorities for redressal. Deputy Mayor Srilatha Sobhan Reddy said the authorities should make special efforts in resolving the grievances of the petitioners. She instructed the officials to take steps to ensure speedy justice to the requests from time to time. Of the 43 requests received in the Prajavani programme held at the GHMC headquarters, the Town Planning department received the highest number of complaints at 26, followed by health (4), ENC department (3), tax section, UBD and FA departments (2 each) and legal, lakes, HMWSSB, LWSB, LWS and S departments one each.

A total of 103 applications were received in the six zones under the GHMC limits. Of these, 62 complaints were received in Kukatpally zone, 19 in Serilingampally zone, 11 in LB Nagar zone, four in Secunderabad zone, four in Khairatabad zone and three in Charminar zone.

Additional Commissioners Shiva Kumar Naidu, Nalini Padmavathi, Yadagiri Rao, Venugopal Reddy, Geetha Radhika, Pankaja, Ashok Samrat, Raghu Prasad, Subhadra Devi, CCP Srinivas, CE Bhaskar Reddy, Additional CCP Gangadhar, Lakes SE Narayana, CM&amp;HO Dr Padmaja, Veterinary Chief Dr Abdul Vakil, Joint Commissioners Mahesh Kulkarni, Uma Prakash, Vanisree, Water Works D G Housing SE Krishna Rao, PV Ramana, Rajeshwar, UBD Director

Srinivas and Advertising Officer Durdana Begum were present.</text><top_image>https://www.bizzbuzz.news/h-upload/2024/11/11/1942884-ghmc-mayor.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.bizzbuzz.news/news-capsules/prajavani-to-solve-peoples-problems-ghmc-mayor-gadwal-vijayalakshmi-1341911</link></article><article><title>BRS MLA makes his way back to party, setback for Congress, CM Revanth Reddy</title><authors>Pushkar Banakar, Cdata, Var Template_Content, Sso_Login_Box, Xwelcome Backorenter The Email Address Or Mobile Number Associated With Your Account To Sign In. Show Passwordsign Innew To The Indian Express Signupxcreate Your Account It Is Quick, Easy.Or Show Passwordnextvalidate Otpregisteralready Have An Account, Signin, Sso_Social_Box, Sign In Withgmailfacebookapple, Var Follow_Widget_Data</authors><publish_date>2024-07-30</publish_date><text>LESS THAN a month after joining the Congress, Gadwal MLA B Krishna Mohan Reddy returned to the Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) Tuesday, bringing some cheer to the beleaguered party.

Reddy was one of the 10 MLAs to leave the BRS after the party’s drubbing in last year’s Assembly elections, where the K Chandrashekar Rao (KCR)-led outfit was reduced to 39 seats in the 117-member House. The BRS has raised the issue with Speaker Gaddam Prasad but no action has been taken against the turncoats yet.

BRS leader Dasoju Srravan, who welcomed Krishna Reddy back into the party, told The Indian Express: “His return is a good sign and was bound to happen as the BRS sustained his political life. It just shows how Telangana Chief Minister Revanth Reddy is violating the anti-defection law. The Gadwal MLA’s return will open the doors for other leaders to return. They have realised their mistake and several of them are in touch with the high command.”

Advertisement

Krishna Reddy’s departure is also a personal setback for Revanth Reddy as his Gadwal seat falls in the erstwhileMahbubnagar district, which is the CM’s pocketborough.

Many of Krishna Reddy’s supporters admitted that they too were surprised at his latest switch. “While he had discussed his move to the Congress with the cadre and second-rung leadership, there were no discussions about him going back to the BRS. However, it is true that the second-rung leadership was not very happy with him joining the Congress,” Mandal Parishad President (MPP) of Gadwal and BRS leader Prathap Goud told The Indian Express.

Krishna Reddy began his political career with the Telugu Desam Party (TDP) in 2009 and unsuccessfully contested the GADWAL Assembly seat. He lost to his aunt and then Congress candidate D K Aruna. In 2014, Krishna Reddy again lost from Gadwal to Aruna.

In the 2018 Assembly polls finally, Krishna Reddy defeated Aruna, but his victory was marred by controversy. In August 2023, hearing a plea filed by Aruna, the Telangana High Court annulled his victory for failure to disclose his assets correctly in his election affidavit. The Supreme Court subsequently stayed the High Court order.

Advertisement

In 2022, Krishna Reddy was embroiled in a controversy after he allegedly assaulted and abused a government school principal over the delay in sending him the invitation for the opening ceremony of a school in his constituency.

By 2023, Krishna Reddy had moved to the BRS, and was nominated by the party as its candidate from the Gadwal seat. This time he defeated the Congress’s Sarita Tirupathaiah by just over 7,000 votes.

By March 2019, his aunt Aruna too had switched sides, from the Congress to the BJP. She is currently the Mahabubnagar MP as well as a BJP national vice-president.

BRS sources said Krishna Reddy felt “suffocated” in the Congress, and hence his return to the BRS. “He shared with us how he was being overlooked on a number of things,” an aide said, though admitting that they expected Krishna Reddy and the Congress to “work things out”. “His return to the BRS comes as a shock.”

Advertisement

For BRS leaders, especially those in Gadwal, the move has come as a fresh breath of air. “This is a huge setback for Revanth Reddy. We expect more MLAs to return to the party fold. The Congress can only fool people for a certain amount of time,” a leader in Dharur mandal of Jogulamba Gadwal district said.

Congress sources admitted they did not see the move coming. “Krishna Mohan garu was treated very well in the party. Many times since his joining, he had expressed his happiness. But there was no sign that he wanted to return,” a senior Congress leader said, commenting on the timing ahead of Revanth Reddy’s coming US visit.

Apart from Krishna Reddy, the MLAs to have left the BRS for the Congress since its loss include T Prakash Goud (Rajendranagar), Pocharam Srinivas Reddy (Banswada), Danam Nagender (Khairatabad), Kale Yadaiah (Chevella), Dr Sanjay Kumar (Jagtial), Kadiam Srihari (Station Ghanpur), Tellam Venkat Rao (Bhadrachalam), Arekapudi Gandhi (Serilingampalli) and Gudem Mahipal Reddy (Patancheru).</text><top_image>https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/07/Untitled-design-2-16.jpg</top_image><link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/telangana-brs-mla-makes-his-way-back-setback-for-congress-revanth-reddy-9484514/</link></article><article><title>Gadwal BJP Celebrates 75th Anniversary of Indian Constitution with Floral Tributes to Dr. B.R. Ambedkar</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-11-27</publish_date><text>Gadwal: On the occasion of the 75th anniversary of the adoption of the Indian Constitution, a special program was organized at the BJP District Office located in DK Bungalow, Gadwal town. Dr. B.R. Ambedkar's portrait and a copy of the Constitution were adorned with floral garlands as a tribute.

District President Ramachandra Reddy addressed the gathering, emphasizing the uniqueness and greatness of the Indian Constitution. He remarked, “While constitutions of many countries have undergone several amendments, India’s Constitution remains resilient and continues to guide the nation as envisioned by Dr. Ambedkar. This is a testament to the brilliance of Dr. Ambedkar and the strength of our country. Many nations admire the Indian Constitution for its revolutionary approach.”

He further highlighted, “The Indian Constitution is a visionary document aimed at the comprehensive development of the nation. Dr. B.R. Ambedkar dedicated his time, intellect, and even sacrificed his health for the drafting of this remarkable Constitution.”

The event concluded with District General Secretary Ravikumar Ekbote leading all participants in a collective reading of the Preamble to the Constitution.

Prominent attendees included former Assembly Convener Ramanjaneyulu, Town President Bandala Venkata Ramulu, District OBC Morcha President Deva Das, State BJYM Committee Member Delhiwala Krishna, BJYM District Leaders Kottala Veeresh Reddy, Town Vice President Pandu Reddy, OBC Morcha Vice President Dabbileti Narasimha, senior BJP leaders Geeta Reddy, Mohan Reddy, Ramesh, and Kurvapalli Srinu, among others.

The program was a solemn and inspirational tribute to Dr. Ambedkar and the values enshrined in the Indian Constitution.















</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/11/27/1500771-bjp.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/gadwal-bjp-celebrates-75th-anniversary-of-indian-constitution-with-floral-tributes-to-dr-br-ambedkar-924835</link></article><article><title>Another U-turn by BRS MLA Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy: now expresses desire to continue in Congress</title><authors>Authors</authors><publish_date>2024-08-01</publish_date><text>Proving the ‘Aayaram Gayaram’ political theory to perfection, Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) MLA of Gadwal Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy, who joined the Congress last month and announced his return to the BRS a couple of days back, has once again expressed his desire to continue in the Congress.

In the backdrop of Mr. Krishnamohan Reddy meeting the BRS working president K.T. Rama Rao in the Assembly on Tuesday and expressing his wish to continue in the BRS, Excise and Tourism Minister Jupally Krishna Rao met him at his residence over breakfast and apparently convinced him to continue in the Congress.

Mr. Reddy is said to have agreed to the proposal but he expressed his displeasure over some Congress leaders in the constituency opposing his entry into the party. Moreover, he had to convince his supporters that he had joined the Congress for development of the constituency and Government had to do something in that direction. The Minister promised him that development of the constituency was not an issue at all.

CM’s dinner meet with BRS MLAs who joined Congress

This meeting comes after a dinner meeting of Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy on Wednesday night with the BRS MLAs who joined the Congress, at the residence of Mr. Pocharam Srinivas Reddy, who is one of the defectors. The dinner meeting also attended by a few Congress Ministers who assured them of a good political future in the Congress and also informed them that some more BRS MLAs were willing to join the Congress soon.

To date, 10 BRS MLAs have joined Congress. Of them, Mr. Krishnamohan Reddy was the first one to have returned to BRS and now takes another U-turn.</text><top_image>https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/cn0rmp/article68471942.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_Gadwal_MLA_Bandla_Kr_5_1_KSD17KV1.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/another-u-turn-by-brs-mla-bandla-krishnamohan-reddy-now-expresses-desire-to-continue-in-congress/article68471863.ece</link></article><article><title>Jupally Krishna Rao calls on Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy</title><authors>About The Author</authors><publish_date>2024-08-02</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: Minister Jupally Krishna Rao visited the residence of Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy, among strong rumours that the latter might return to the Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS). The minister's visit is seen as an attempt to persuade the MLA.

Krishna Mohan Reddy had joined the Congress in the presence of Chief Minister Revanth Reddy. Recently, his meeting with BRS working president K.T. Rama Rao sparked speculations about his potential return to the BRS.

The minister's visit to Krishna Mohan Reddy's residence has gained significance in this context.

After joining Congress, Krishna Mohan Reddy reportedly faced issues with local party leaders. Some Gadwal Congress leaders openly opposed his induction. Amidst these challenges and a lack of coordination with Congress, the MLA was dissatisfied, sources said.

A senior BRS leader mentioned that Krishna Mohan Reddy has decided to continue with BRS. The party is hopeful that other MLAs who left BRS might also return to their original fold.</text><top_image>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2024/08/02/1828222-untitleddesign-2024-08-02t090857354.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/jupally-krishna-rao-calls-on-gadwal-mla-krishna-mohan-reddy-1813824</link></article><article><title>Congress leader’s son dies in road accident in Jogulamba Gadwal district</title><authors>Newstap Bureau</authors><publish_date>2024-10-16</publish_date><text>GADWAL: A tragic road accident claimed the life of Patel Ramachandra Reddy (28), the son of former ZPTC member and ex-Congress DCC president Patel Aruna Prabhakar Reddy, in Jogulamba Gadwal district.

The accident occurred near Dyyala Vagu, where his car crashed into a culvert.

Local residents noticed the crash and rushed Ramachandra Reddy to the hospital, but he succumbed to his injuries en route. The incident has left his family in deep grief, and further details about the accident are awaited.

Investigations are underway to determine the cause of the accident.</text><top_image>https://www.newstap.in/h-upload/2024/10/16/1660455-congress-leaders-son-dies-in-road-accident.webp</top_image><link>https://www.newstap.in/crime/congress-leaders-son-dies-in-road-accident-in-jogulamba-gadwal-district-1554859</link></article><article><title>Archaka Maha Sabha in Jogulamba Gadwal District Highlights Key Demands for Priests' Welfare</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-11-24</publish_date><text>Gadwal: In a significant gathering, the Archaka Maha Sabha was held at the Sri Sri Sri Veerabrahmendra Swamy Temple premises in Ieeja Mandal, Jogulamba Gadwal District. This was the first meeting after Chakravarti Acharyulu was elected as the Dhupa Deepa Naivedya District President of Jogulamba Gadwal. Archakas honored him with garlands in recognition of his leadership.

The event was presided over by Chakravarti Acharyulu and attended by the United District Vice-President Ashok Acharyulu. During the meeting, the Archakas discussed continuing their daily services to the deities and highlighted several demands to be presented to the government.

Key Demands Presented by Archakas:

1. Increase in Minimum Salary: The previous BRS government had provided nominal salaries to temple priests. The Archakas urged the current Congress government to increase the minimum salary to ₹22,000.

2. Housing: Archakas without proper housing requested the allocation of land under government schemes like Indiramma Housing.

3. Job Security: Archakas emphasized the need for permanent employment safeguards.

4. Healthcare Benefits: The priests requested free medical treatment for themselves and their family members in case of health issues.

5. Welfare Schemes: Archakas sought access to various government welfare schemes and demanded pressure on the government to ensure their inclusion.

6. Security for Archakas: The priests highlighted the importance of providing security to temple staff.

The meeting concluded with a call for every Archaka to participate in the submission of memorandums to the government for these demands.

Appointments of Mandal In-Charges:

The following appointments were announced for various mandals in the district:

Gattu Mandal In-Charge: Jangam Paramesh,

Maldakal Mandal In-Charge: Guru Venkataswamy,

Ieeja Mandal In-Charge: Nagaraju,

Rajoli Mandal In-Charge: Adavi Swamy,

Gadwal Mandal In-Charge: Naresh Swamy,

The meeting saw active participation from Archakas across the district and was attended by key officials, including United District Vice-President Ashok Acharyulu, United District Secretary Sekharayya Swamy, Gadwal District Honorary President Raghu Sharma, and Panchikala Padu Shiva.

This Maha Sabha underscored the need for government support and the unity of temple priests in addressing their challenges and achieving their goals.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/11/24/1500115-archaka-maha-sabha.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/archaka-maha-sabha-in-jogulamba-gadwal-district-highlights-key-demands-for-priests-welfare-924216</link></article><article><title>Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy meets Revanth Reddy</title><authors>Sandeep Erukala, About The Author</authors><publish_date>2024-08-02</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: Putting an end to reports that Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy was returning to the BRS party, the MLA met with Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy at the latter's residence in Jubilee Hills on Friday. This development comes days after the MLA was seen with BRS MLAs in the assembly, and some reports suggested that the MLA was returning to the BRS after joining Congress a few days ago.

The meeting with Revanth Reddy indicates that the MLA remains with the Congress. Minister Jupalli Krishna Rao, MLAs Kavvampalli Satyanarayana, Adluri Laxman, Madhusudhan Reddy, and former MLA Sampath Kumar were among those who met Revanth Reddy.





</text><top_image>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2024/08/02/1828236-dillydallying.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/gadwal-mla-krishna-mohan-reddy-meets-revanth-reddy-1813835</link></article><article><title>GHMC Mayor Gadwal Vijayalaxmi joins Congress, her father KK to follow soon</title><authors>Authors</authors><publish_date>2024-03-30</publish_date><text>Mayor of Greater Hyderabad Municipal Corporation(GHMC), Gadwal Vijayalaxmi, the daughter of Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) general secretary K. Keshava Rao, joined Congress on Saturday in the presence of Telangana Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy, All India Congress Committee (AICC) in-charge for the State Deepa Das Munshi and other leaders.

Mr. Keshava Rao, a senior leader in BRS has already informed his decision to come back to Congress where he started his political journey five decades ago. He met with Mr. Revanth Reddy on Friday and later claimed that his homecoming was like a pilgrim returning home after a long journey.

#Hyderabad | GHMC Mayor Gadwal Vijayalaxmi joins Congress, her father KK to follow soon



Ms. Vijayalaxmi's entry will boost the Congress party's numbers in GHMC council as several BRS Corporators are expected to follow her soon@rravikanthreddy's report👇https://t.co/xRSLqhiba2pic.twitter.com/TUJVIYEEZT — The Hindu-Hyderabad (@THHyderabad) March 30, 2024

The father-daughter duo’s decision to join the Congress is not surprising. The news about their joining the Congress began when Ms. Munshi met with Ms. Vijayalaxmi in Hyderabad on March 22 at her residence in Hyderabad where Mr. Keshava Rao was also present. Later, Mr. Rao met with AICC president Mallikarjun Kharge in New Delhi.

Their induction has triggered an intense response from BRS leaders who have demanded their resignation from the posts they hold. However, Mr. Rao’s son K. Viplav Kumar remains with BRS and has announced that he would work under the party president K. Chandrashekhar Rao. At a press conference held on Friday, Mr. Kumar faulted the decision taken by his father and sister to shift to Congress. He too suggested them to resign from the posts they have now as BRS members before joining Congress.

Mr. Keshava Rao also expressed his desire to resign as a Rajya Sabha member as he was elected on behalf of the BRS party and contest in the by poll if Congress gives him another chance. He held senior positions in the Congress before joining the BRS a few months before the formation of Telangana. He served as a Minister in several Congress governments and was later appointed president of the Andhra Pradesh Pradesh Congress Committee (APCC) in the combined state.

The Congress may not benefit from their induction numbers-wise, but it would be a big jolt to the BRS which is already struggling with desertions ahead of the Parliament elections. Ms. Vijayalakshmi’s entry will boost the Congress party’s numbers in the GHMC council as several BRS Corporators are expected to follow her soon. Former GHMC Deputy Mayor Baba Fasiuddin, a close follower of BRS working president K.T. Rama Rao, has already joined the Congress.

The BRS, which has won the majority of MLA seats in the GHMC area, will face a tough task in retaining the MLAs as the Congress claimed that several MLAs were in touch with them to jump the ship. It is expected that once the defections begin, the Corporators too would join the stream. Khairatabad BRS MLA Danam Nagander, a former Congress man has already deserted the party.</text><top_image>https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/cities/Hyderabad/wzhp5o/article68008913.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Gadwal%20Vijayalaxmi%20mayor%20of%20Greater%20Hyderabad%20Municipal%20Corporation%20joins%20Congress%20in%20the%20presence%20of%20Telangana%20Chief%20Minister%20Revanth%20Reddy.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/ghmc-mayor-gadwal-vijayalaxmi-joins-congress-her-father-kk-to-follow-soon/article68008894.ece</link></article><article><title>Farmers protest in Gadwal over delayed Rythu Bharosa payments</title><authors>Newstap Bureau</authors><publish_date>2024-10-25</publish_date><text>GADWAL: Farmers in Jogulamba Gadwal district, led by Nadigadda Hakkula Porata Samithi Chairman Gongala Ranjith Kumar, protested outside the Collector's office on Friday, expressing frustration over the Congress government's failure to deposit Rythu Bharosa funds as promised before the Dussehra festival.

Ranjith Kumar, joined by around 200 farmers, criticised the delay, calling it "unacceptable."

Ranjith Kumar stated that the government's commitment to provide Rs 2 lakh loan waivers for farmers has so far remained unfulfilled. He further accused the authorities of ignoring farmers' grievances, alleging that the district Collector and police had dismissed requests to discuss these pressing issues.

The protestors also criticised what they see as a lack of empathy from officials, contrasting the current handling of farmer grievances with a recent incident in Bijwaram village, where police facilitated a young girl's funeral with heavy security. Farmers expressed anger at being barred from discussing their issues at the Collector's office, claiming this reflects poorly on the Congress administration’s approach to governance.

The protesters demanded an immediate resolution to the pending Rythu Bharosa disbursements, urging the government to address farmers' financial needs without further delay.</text><top_image>https://www.newstap.in/h-upload/2024/10/25/1662696-farmers-protest-in-gadwal.webp</top_image><link>https://www.newstap.in/telangana/farmers-protest-in-gadwal-over-delayed-rythu-bharosa-payments-1556020</link></article><article><title>BRS Leaders Demand Justice for Minor Girl’s Death in Gadwal, Urge Action Against Seed Organizer</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-11-05</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Telangana: Senior Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) leaders, including Dr. RS Praveen Kumar and former state minister Srinivas Goud, Nagar Doddi Venkatramudu , Anjaneyulu Goud,NHPS Ranjit Kumar have voiced strong demands for justice following the tragic death of Vaddera Rajeshwari, a minor girl from Bijwaram village, Maldakal Mandal. Rajeshwari reportedly took her own life after alleged harassment and false accusations of theft by her employer, a prominent local seed organizer.

The incident has sparked widespread public and political outcry, with allegations of police negligence and favoritism due to the accused’s influential connections. According to reports, Rajeshwari was employed as a domestic worker at the home of Bandla Rajasekhar Reddy, a known seed organizer in Gadwal. The family and BRS leaders allege that Reddy accused her of theft, pressuring her under the weight of unsubstantiated claims. Unable to bear the humiliation, Rajeshwari is said to have consumed pesticide, which led to her tragic death.

BRS leaders, along with activists from the Nadigadda Rights Struggle Committee, visited Rajeshwari’s family to offer condolences and pledged their support in seeking justice. During the visit, Dr. RS Praveen Kumar condemned the alleged mistreatment of the minor girl and criticized the police for initially omitting Reddy’s name from the First Information Report (FIR). He accused local law enforcement of showing bias by protecting the accused due to his political influence.

Addressing the media, Dr. Kumar called for immediate and strict action against Reddy, along with an impartial investigation into the role of

local police officers who allegedly mishandled the case. "We will not rest until those responsible for this innocent girl's death are brought to justice," he stated, adding that justice for Rajeshwari should serve as a deterrent to prevent the exploitation of minors in the future.

Former minister Srinivas Goud echoed these sentiments, demanding that Reddy be held accountable for his actions. "Exploitation and abuse of vulnerable communities cannot be tolerated. We will ensure this case does not go ignored," he said.Local activists and leaders from multiple organizations held a rally in support of Rajeshwari's family, urging authorities to investigate the broader influence of seed organizers in the district. They argue that some powerful figures use their connections to avoid accountability, further marginalizing vulnerable groups.

The BRS leaders also highlighted the need for stronger protections for minors, calling on the government to address the prevalence of child labor and exploitation in rurallabor and exploitation in rural areas. They expressed concerns that Rajeshwari's case represents broader issues facing marginalized families in Telangana, urging the state to implement policies to protect children from similar fates.

As the case continues to unfold, calls for a fair and transparent investigation grow louder, with the BRS leadership pledging to pursue justice relentlessly. Rajeshwari's death has not only brought attention to her personal tragedy but has also sparked a wider Conversation about child exploitation and power dynamics, and police accountability.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/11/05/1494517-whatsapp-image-2024-11-05-at-65753-am.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/brs-leaders-demand-justice-for-minor-girls-death-in-gadwal-urge-action-against-seed-organizer-919193</link></article><article><title>Bathukamma Event: Hyderabad Mayor Gadwal Vijayalaxmi booked for allowing high-decibel music</title><authors>Authors</authors><publish_date>2024-10-14</publish_date><text>The Hyderabad Mayor, Gadwal Vijayalaxmi, is facing legal scrutiny after allegations surfaced of her organising and using a loud music system at a Bathukamma event last week in Banjara Hills. Police said that the Mayor allegedly interfered when the police reached the place on Road Number 12 and asked the sound system organisers to reduce the volume.

The incident took place in NBT Nagar, where the event organisers were reportedly violating a citywide ban on DJ systems during religious processions and festivals. Police arrived at the venue around 11:30 p.m. on Thursday and instructed the organisers to shut down the equipment. However, the organisers allegedly refused to comply when the Mayor interfered with the police.

“A case has been registered for violating noise pollution regulations against the organisers and the sound system operator. Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakaxmi was booked for abetment,” clarified a senior officer from West Zone police.</text><top_image>https://th-i.thgim.com/public/todays-paper/tp-national/tp-telangana/u9c08s/article64993547.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Non-allocation-GOU9F1CKV3jpgjpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Hyderabad/hyderabad-mayor-booked-for-allowing-high-decibel-music-at-bathukamma-event/article68750145.ece</link></article><article><title>Saritha Tirupatiah Extends Diwali Greetings to CM Revanth Reddy, Advocates for Gadwal's Development</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-11-01</publish_date><text>Gadwal: On the occasion of Diwali, Chief Minister Revanth Reddy received warm greetings from Nagarkurnool Member of Parliament Dr. Mallu Ravi, former ZP Chairperson and Gadwal Constituency Congress In-charge Saritha Tirupatiah, along with other dignitaries. Saritha Tirupatiah met with the Chief Minister to extend festive wishes, hoping for a brighter future for Gadwal, with the Diwali lamps symbolizing the removal of darkness and the ushering in of positive change for the region.

During the meeting, Saritha expressed her vision of replacing the "darkness" of the past decade with the "light" of good governance, aiming to bring significant development and welfare to Gadwal and Telangana. She urged the Chief Minister to lead initiatives that will fill the lives of the people with renewed hope and prosperity. Also present at the meeting were Minister Seethakka, Achampet MLA Chikudu Vamsikrishna, and other prominent leaders.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/11/01/1493780-saritha.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/saritha-tirupatiah-extends-diwali-greetings-to-cm-revanth-reddy-advocates-for-gadwals-development-918579</link></article><article><title>HC prods officials to probe major scam</title><authors>The Hans India</authors><publish_date>2024-10-24</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Acase has been registered following the orders of the High Court in connection with a double claim scam related to the land acquisition of the Nettempadu Lift Irrigation Scheme. The scam, amounting to crores of rupees, took place between 2016 and 2018.

Gadwal Court Superintendent Satyanarayana allegedly made nine fraudulent entries under his wife Lalitha’s name and illegally transferred money into accounts.

With the case now registered, it is expected that more names from within the Gadwal court might emerge in connection with this scandal. Since the fraud occurred within the judicial department, it had previously gone unnoticed.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/24/1491716-scam.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/hc-prods-officials-to-probe-major-scam-916658</link></article><article><title>Gadwal BRS MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy Joins Congress</title><authors>Dc Online Team, About The Author</authors><publish_date>2024-07-06</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: In yet another shock to BRS party in the state, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy joined Congress in the presencein the presence of Telangana chief minister A. Revanth Reddy and other Congress leaders on Saturday. He is the Seventh BRS MLA to join Congress, bringing down the number of BRS MLAs to 31.

Besides Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy, BRS MLAs Yadaiah (Chevella), Pocharam Srinivas Reddy (Banswada) and Sanjay Kumar (Jagtial), Danam Nagender ( Khairatabad), Kadiam Srihari (Station Ghanpur) and Tellam Venkat Rao (Bhadrachalam) had joined the Congress.



</text><top_image>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2024/07/06/1101965-bandla.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/gadwal-brs-mla-bandla-krishna-mohan-reddy-joins-congress-1808805</link></article><article><title>Assistant Engineer of Panchayat Raj department in Gadwal district held for graft</title><authors>Authors</authors><publish_date>2024-11-18</publish_date><text>The Mahabubnagar Unit of the Anti-Corruption Bureau (ACB) apprehended an Assistant Engineer of the Panchayat Raj department in Gadwal district on Monday while he was accepting a bribe of ₹50,000.

According to the ACB, the engineer, identified as Pandu Ranga Rao, demanded the bribe from a complainant in exchange for recording the measurement book and forwarding the bill for the construction of a minority community hall.

“The ACB recovered the bribe amount from the engineer’s possession and conducted a chemical test on his hands and pockets, which yielded positive results,” read a release from the agency.

The accused was subsequently arrested and produced before the Special Court for SPE and ACB cases in Nampally, Hyderabad.

The ACB urged the public to report any instance of bribery or corruption by public servants to their toll-free number 1064. The identity of the complainant will be kept confidential.</text><top_image>https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/og-image.png</top_image><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/assistant-engineer-of-panchayat-raj-department-in-gadwal-district-held-for-graft/article68881880.ece</link></article><article><title>New Bharosa Centres Launched in Mahbubnagar and Jogulamba Gadwal Districts</title><authors>Dc Correspondent, About The Author</authors><publish_date>2024-11-13</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: The police women safety wing (WSW) opened a Bharosa centre for Mahbubnagar district while a building was inaugurated for the existing unit at the Jogulamba Gadwal district. The Bharosa Centres, managed by the Society for Protection of Women and Children, with WSW DGP Shikha Goel as member-secretary, offers specialised support for victims. Each centre, staffed with professionals including counsellors, psychologists, legal officers, and medical personnel, ensures comprehensive care.</text><top_image>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2024/11/12/1862088-bharosa.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/new-bharosa-centres-launched-in-mahbubnagar-and-jogulamba-gadwal-districts-1837710</link></article><article><title>President of Dhupa Deepa Naivedya Archaka Sangham, Jogulamba Gadwal District, Comments on Tirumala Laddu Adulteration.</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-09-26</publish_date><text>Gadwal : Chakravarti Swamy, President of the Dhupa Deepa Naivedya Archaka Sangham in Jogulamba Gadwal District, recently commented on the adulteration issue involving Tirumala Tirupati Devasthanam (TTD) laddus. He expressed that such an incident could not have occurred without the involvement of the TTD Executive Officer, the temple administration, and even the state's cabinet and endowments department. He emphasized that adulterating laddus is not a minor issue and raised concerns about the influence of the Endowments Department on Hindu temples.





Swamy criticized the government for bringing only temples with significant revenue under the control of the Endowments Department, while ignoring thousands of temples with no income. He lamented that many temples are struggling to provide basic offerings like incense, lamps, and food offerings, and lack proper upkeep and patronage. He questioned why only Hindu temples are being managed under the Endowments Department in a secular country and why churches and mosques are not subjected to the same control.



Swamy further expressed concern that in rural areas, many temples do not conduct regular rituals, which is leading Hindu youth astray, pushing them toward addictions like alcohol and drugs. He urged parents to teach their children devotion and instill religious values from a young age, suggesting that families should visit temples regularly. He stressed that at least once a week, families should visit a temple to receive blessings, which would not only ensure the well-being and health of their families but also guide children on the right path and contribute to building a better society.

Swamy also announced the launch of the "Mana Gudi Mana Dharma" (Our Temple, Our Religion) program in Alampur Mandal, Jogulamba Gadwal District, to raise awareness among Hindu families about their religious duties. Under this initiative, weekly gatherings will be held at different temples, where collective worship, devotional songs, and bhajans will be conducted to promote the revival of Hindu values. He called on every Hindu citizen, at the village, state, and national levels, to take responsibility for spreading and protecting Sanatana Dharma.



Pulikal Veeresh and Chagadona Satish, among others, participated in the program.

</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/09/26/1483822-tirumala-laddu.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/president-of-dhupa-deepa-naivedya-archaka-sangham-jogulamba-gadwal-district-comments-on-tirumala-laddu-adulteration-909940</link></article><article><title>Jogulamba Gadwal Police Conducts Open House to Raise Awareness Among Students on Policing and Public Safety</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-10-24</publish_date><text>Gadwal: "Students should not only focus on academics but also increase awareness about society and the services provided by the police" - District SP Mr. T. Srinivasa Rao, IPS

As part of Police Martyrs’ Remembrance (Police Flag Day), the District SP, Mr. T. Srinivasa Rao, IPS, participated in the final day of the Open House event organized at the Police Parade Ground, aimed at raising awareness among students.

Addressing the students who visited the Open House stalls, the District SP emphasized the importance of students being active in academics and being aware of the developments in society as well as the services provided by the police department. Around 600 students from SR International School and Social Welfare Schools visited the stalls on the third and final day of the Open House.

Speaking on the occasion, the SP stated that the three-day Open House program was organized to make students aware of the police department's operations and the various services it offers to the public. He stressed the need for students to understand what a police station is, its role in maintaining law and order, and how it functions. For this purpose, stalls featuring SHE Teams, Cyber Security Wing, Communication, Anti-Drug Unit, Arms Exhibition, Dog Squad, and Bomb Disposal were set up to educate the students.

The SP also advised the students to focus on their future goals, study diligently, and use mobile phones only when necessary. He warned against opening suspicious links or sharing photos online, as this could lead to photo morphing and cybercrimes.

Key Topics Covered During the Event:

The concept of Friendly Policing and how beat and patrolling systems work day and night to maintain public safety and order.

The introduction of modern technology like face recognition systems and portable fingerprint devices to easily identify criminals.

The role of CCTV cameras in preventing crimes and solving cases swiftly.

How SHE Teams and Bharosa Centers work to protect women and girls.

Demonstrations of police weaponry, how they function, and when they are used.

The role of bomb squads in defusing explosives.

Precautions against Cyber Crimes, such as avoiding contact with strangers online and immediately reporting incidents to the Cyber Crime helpline number, 1930.

How dogs help in identifying criminals, thieves, and explosives.

Officers from various police departments, including the bomb squad, IT Core, Bharosa staff, SHE Teams, Fingerprints, and Communication teams, educated the students about the operations of the police department.

The event was attended by Armed Forces DSP Narendra Rao, RI Venkatesh, Harif, and RSI officers, along with 600 students and teachers from SR School and Social Welfare School.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/24/1491842-police.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/jogulamba-gadwal-police-conducts-open-house-to-raise-awareness-among-students-on-policing-and-public-safety-916778</link></article><article><title>Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi pats youth for saving occupants from sinking car</title><authors>The Hans India</authors><publish_date>2024-07-17</publish_date><text>Hyderabad:Greater Hyderabad Muni cipal Corporation (GHMC) Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi said that youth should be at the forefront of community service. The Mayor congratulated and honoured the youth at the head office of GHMC and presented them shawls on Tuesday.The youth had rescued people who were in a car that was being swept away by the flood waters in Musheerabad.

On this occasion, Vijayalakshmi asked them about the details of how they rescued from the sinking car. She appreciated the initiative and bravery of intermediate students Praneet Yadav, Mohan Yadav, Nagaraju Chari, and M Martin who alerted them to the accident. Everyone should be responsible and have a desire to help other people, she said.

They were advised to be careful about themselves as well as protect others. She requested them to provide more such services where necessary in the future.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2023/07/07/1363419-gadwal-vijayalakshmi.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/news/cities/hyderabad/mayor-gadwal-vijayalakshmi-pats-youth-for-saving-occupants-from-sinking-car-892491</link></article><article><title>Lack of support from Telangana Congress, Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy switches back to BRS</title><authors>Kaniza Garari</authors><publish_date>2024-07-31</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: With panchayat elections round the corner, MLAs who switched from Bharat Rashtra Samithi to the Congress party in Telangana are feeling the heat as the Congress cadre is not supporting them.

Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy has returned back to BRS as there is a lot of angst and anger against him in the Congress cadre.

The cadre has strongly objected to his inclusion in the party, and at the ground level, there is no cooperation extended to him. Due to this, Reddy met with the BRS working president, K T Rama Rao, on Tuesday and said that he would continue in BRS only.

Ghar Wapsi to BRS

The return of BRS MLA is being seen as a setback to the ruling Congress party which had managed to switch 10 MLA's on their side.

Ghar Wapsi was prompted by the constant resistance of the Congress cadre. G Niranjan, senior vice-president of the Congress party, says, "The cadre was not happy with him as they have been fighting against him for the last 10 years. How is it possible for them to now embrace him? Also, his presence would mean that the state leadership would be guided by what he portrays to them. This was not acceptable to the cadre."

Panchayat elections

The panchayat elections are round the corner and those who are close to the MLA's in the constituency will play a major role. The Congress workers in Gadwal are queuing up with their representative. Congress MLA contestant Saritha Thirupataiah lost the election with a margin of 7036 votes and she has been opposing the presence of BRS MLA in the party.

"All these factors will play a major role in the panchayat elections," explained sources in Congress.

Opposition of senior Congress leader Jeevan Reddy

Senior Congress leader Jeevan Reddy also strongly opposed the inclusion of BRS MLA Dr Sanjiv Kumar in the party from Jagityal constituency. He was upset over the party welcoming his political rival and BRS MLA Dr A Sanjay Kumar without his knowledge. Jeevan Reddy threatened to quit the party. Senior Congress leaders of Telangana deputy chief minister Bhatti Vikramarka, information minister Sridhar Babu and other leaders first tried to placate him. Finally chief minister Revanth Reddy also met him in Delhi along with AICC in-charge for Telangana Deepa Dasmunshi.

Revanth Reddy pointed out that confusion arose as PCC did not take necessary steps on political developments happening in the Jagtial Assembly segment. He claimed that there was a misunderstanding and both Central and State leadership of Congress have assured Jeevan Reddy that his role and importance within the party would remain intact. The Congress government would also seek suggestions and advice from Jeevan Reddy.

In the case of Krishna Mohan Reddy, due to the strong resistance from cadre, it is alleged that chief minister Revanth Reddy also sidelined him.



Background

BRS had won 39 of the total 119 Assembly constituencies in the elections, while Congress came to power winning 64 seats.

However, BRS MLA from Secunderabad Cantonment, G Lasya Nanditha, died in a road accident earlier this year. Congress won the by-poll for the Secunderabad Cantonment Assembly segment. This led to an increase in its strength to 65.

With addition of 10 BRS MLAs who crossed over to Congress, its strength rose to 75. However, Reddy has returned to the BRS fold. Others who are not getting support are also planning to come back to BRS, according to sources.

Six BRS MLCs have also joined the ruling party recently. With these defections, Congress' strength goes up to 10 in the 40-member Legislative Council.</text><top_image>https://newsmeter.in/h-upload/2024/07/31/378241-picsart24-07-3118-01-53-938.webp</top_image><link>https://newsmeter.in/politics/lack-of-support-from-telangana-congress-gadwal-mla-krishna-mohan-reddy-switches-back-to-brs-733360</link></article><article><title>Gadwal MLA Inaugurates Grand Rathotsavam of Pagunta Venkanna Swami with Devotees.</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-11-02</publish_date><text>Gadwal : Grand Celebration of Pagunta Venkanna Swami Rathotsavam MLA Participates in the Rathotsavam Special Poojas for Sri Sri Sri Lakshmi Venkateshwara Swami Today, on the occasion of the Brahmotsavam and annual festival of Sri Sri Pagunta Lakshmi Venkateshwara Swami in KT Doddi Mandal of Gadwal constituency, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy visited the temple, offered special poojas to the deity, and received blessings.

After the rituals, the MLA conducted poojas for the chariot and personally initiated the Rathotsavam by pulling the chariot to commence the festival.

Addressing the gathering, the MLA said:

“The festive season of Telangana has begun. The Brahmotsavam (annual festival) of Sri Sri Sri Pagunta Lakshmi Venkateshwara Swami has started in Venkatapuram village of KT Doddi Mandal, Jogulamba Gadwal district. From today, the festive spirit will spread across Telangana.”

With the blessings of Sri Lakshmi Venkateshwara Swami, I sincerely pray that all farmers and citizens be blessed with health, prosperity, and peace, thriving with abundant crops and happiness for many years to come.

He assured that all arrangements have been made to provide every facility for the devotees attending the festival.

Participating in the program were Agricultural Market Committee Chairman Kurava Hanumanthu, Senior Congress leader Gaddam Krishna Reddy, former MPP Vijay, former Sarpanch Anjaneyulu, leaders Chakradhar Rao Urukundu, Naveen Reddy, Yugandhar Goud, Rajesh, Chandrasekhar Reddy, Gopal Reddy, Chandrasekhar, Amaresh, Gopi, Shekhar Reddy, Pawan Reddy, Govindu, other leaders, activists, and youth members.















</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/11/02/1494012-untitled-1.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/gadwal-mla-inaugurates-grand-rathotsavam-of-pagunta-venkanna-swami-with-devotees-918797</link></article><article><title>Thota Srinivasa Rao takes charge as SP of Gadwal district</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-06-21</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Mr. Thota Srinivasa Rao, IPS, has taken charge as the new Superintendent of Police (SP) of Jogulamba Gadwal district. Upon his arrival at the district police office, he was warmly welcomed with flowers by District DSPs Satyanarayana and Narender Rao. The AR police officials also honored him with a salute.

Mr. Rao, a 2007 batch Group-1 officer, has previously served as DSP in Paderu and Janagama, and as Officer on Special Duty (OSD) in Nandigama, Krishna District, and Kothagudem.

Mr. Thota Srinivasa Rao, IPS, has taken charge as the new Superintendent of Police (SP) of Jogulamba Gadwal district. Upon his arrival at the district police office, he was welcomed with flowers by District DSPs Satyanarayana and Narender Rao, followed by a salute from the AR police officials.

Mr. Rao, a 2007 batch Group-1 officer, has previously served as DSP in Paderu and Janagama, and as Officer on Special Duty (OSD) in Nandigama, Krishna District, and Kothagudem. He was promoted to Additional SP and later to SP while serving in the State Intelligence Department, where he also served as SP and as ADC to the Governor. After being promoted to IPS in 2013, he served as DCP of Cyberabad Traffic in CID and as Balanagar Law &amp; Order DCP. As part of his recent transfer, he has now taken charge as District SP. Following the formalities, inspector officers and SSIs of the district also presented flowers to the new SP.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/06/21/1456402-2.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/thota-srinivasa-rao-takes-charge-as-sp-of-gadwal-district-886424</link></article><article><title>Jogulamba Gadwal District Establishes Vishwa Hindu Parishad Dharma Prasara District Committee</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-11-11</publish_date><text>A meeting was held in Jogulamba Gadwal district to establish the Dharma Prasara District Committee of the Vishwa Hindu Parishad (VHP). Key topics discussed in the meeting included spreading awareness about Dharma, addressing the risks associated with religious conversions, facilitating homecoming (re-conversion) programs, conducting satsangs, and outlining the committee's responsibilities and planned tours.

The event saw the participation of notable figures including R. Jagadishwar Reddy, Narasimhulu, Sudhakar, VHP District Co-Secretary Manoj Kumar Reddy, District Satsang Co-Leader Parusharam, and members of the Dharma Prasara Committees from Dharur and Maldakal mandals.





Delete Edit



</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/11/11/1496056-b.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/jogulamba-gadwal-district-establishes-vishwa-hindu-parishad-dharma-prasara-district-committee-920668</link></article><article><title>HYDRA Should Expand Statewide: Kommula Praveen Raj</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-08-28</publish_date><text>Gadwal: HYDRA Should Not Only Focus on Lakes but Also Target Encroached Government Lands, Properties, and Illegal Constructions.

Kommula Praveen Raj, District President of Teenmaar Mallanna Team in Jogulamba Gadwal.

In a press conference held today at the Jogulamba Gadwal district headquarters, *Kommula Praveen Raj* expressed his support for the work being carried out by the HYDRA organization in Hyderabad. He praised the efforts and emphasized that HYDRA should not be confined to Hyderabad alone but should be expanded to every village in Telangana state.

Praveen Raj urged Chief Minister Revanth Reddy, who is currently acting as the chairman of HYDRA, to take the initiative to expand HYDRA's operations statewide. He also suggested appointing a capable officer like Ranganath to oversee the organization. The focus should be on reclaiming lakes and government lands that have been illegally occupied, demolishing unauthorized constructions, and ensuring that encroached lands are returned to the rightful owners, particularly the poor.

Praveen Raj called for immediate action against those involved in these illegal activities, including the officials who have supported such encroachments. He demanded that these individuals be removed from their positions and imprisoned to serve as a deterrent to others.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/08/28/1475353-praveen.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/hydra-should-expand-statewide-kommula-praveen-raj-902960</link></article><article><title>Double Standards for Citizens and Mayor: A Tale of Contradicting Rules</title><authors>Fouzia Farhana</authors><publish_date>2024-10-11</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: In a glaring example of double standards, the Hyderabad police, who recently imposed a strict ban on DJs during public events, allowed an exception for GHMC Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi during the Bathukamma festival. While ordinary citizens were prohibited from using loud music systems, the mayor led a celebration with blaring DJ music, causing an uproar among observers.

The controversy deepened further when Mayor Vijayalakshmi was seen wielding a sword during the event, making provocative remarks. “Even if the police come, they can’t do anything. Today I hold this sword, and tomorrow, you will,” she declared, in a tone that many perceived as inciting aggressions.

In a glaring example of double standards, the Hyderabad police, who recently imposed a strict ban on DJs during public events, allowed an exception for GHMC Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi during the Bathukamma festival.

pic.twitter.com/eYxMzyCx6d — The Munsif Daily (@munsifdigital) October 11, 2024

Despite the police’s strict enforcement of rules for the general public, they seemed powerless to act in this instance, raising questions about unequal treatment between ordinary citizens and political figures. This incident has sparked widespread criticism, with citizens questioning the fairness of the rules and calling for accountability from those in power.

As this unfolds, the public awaits a response from the authorities, as the contrast between the regulations imposed on them and the apparent freedom enjoyed by officials becomes more evident.</text><top_image>https://2c31032a.delivery.rocketcdn.me/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/MAYOR-VIAYALAKSHMI.jpg</top_image><link>https://munsifdaily.com/double-standards-for-citizens-and-mayor-a-tale-of-contradicting-rules/</link></article><article><title>Asst Engineer in ACB Net for Taking Rs 50k Bribe</title><authors>Dc Correspondent, About The Author</authors><publish_date>2024-11-18</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: The Anti-Corruption Bureau (ACB) on Monday arrested Itikyal mandal assistant engineer for accepting a bribe of Rs 50,000 for doing an official favour. The tainted officer was attached to the panchayat raj department in Gadwal district.

D. Pandu Ranga Rao was caught red-handed while accepting Rs 50,000 bribe from a complainant, who had produced the maintenance book and bills related to minority community hall construction work, before him for clearance.

Officials seized the chemical-laced cash and conducted a test. The fingers of the accused officer tested positive. He was arrested and produced before a court for judicial remand.</text><top_image>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2024/11/18/1863793-untitleddesign5.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/gadwal-panchayat-raj-department-ae-in-acb-net-1839257</link></article><article><title>Gadwal MLA ghar wapsi on hold? Mohan Reddy gets CM Revanth’s support</title><authors>Kaniza Garari</authors><publish_date>2024-08-02</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy met chief minister A Revanth Reddy who assured him that all support would be given and he must stay with the Congress party.

Krishna Mohan Reddy on July 31 met Bharat Rashtra Samithi working president KT Rama Rao in the Assembly office. A public statement stated that, Reddy was returning to BRS and that he met KTR for the same.

Back door meetings

Minister Jupally Krishna Rao met Krishna Mohan Reddy the next day and assured him that all support would be extended to him.

Krishna Mohan Reddy who is representing Gadwal is said to have expressed his displeasure as there was no support from the Congress cadre. The cadre is not supporting him as they have been fighting against him for 10 years. Congress MLA contestant Saritha Thirupathaiah is also strongly objecting to his presence in the party.

These issues would be resolved, Krishna Rao assured him.

Meeting with other 9 MLAs

A meeting with nine other MLAs from BRS who have joined Congress is also on the cards. These are MLAs who contested from the BRS party, won the election and switched over to Congress after the 2024 Lok Sabha elections.

The 10 MLAs are Kadiyam Srihari from the Ghanpur Station Assembly Constituency, Danam Nagender (Khairatabad), Tellam Venkat Rao (Bhadrachalam), Pocharam Srinivas Reddy (Banswada), M Sanjay Kumar (Jagtial), Kale Yadaiah (Chevella), Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy (Gadwal), Prakash Goud (Rajendra Nagar), Arakepudi Gandhi (Serilingampally) and Gudem Mahipal Reddy (Patancheru).

This switch is not being taken easily by Congress cadre at the ground level. They have made it difficult for the new MLAs to function in the constituency.

BRS MLAs have told Krishna Rao that they are not being respected by the Congress cadre.

Rao has assured them that all the issues will be sorted out after chief minister Revanth Reddy’s USA trip.

Three MLAs were ready for Ghar Wapsi

Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy’s step was to be replicated by Dr Sanjiv Kumar from Jagtial and Chevella MLA Kale Yadaiah.

Both these MLAs are feeling the heat from the Congress cadre as they do not have any support on the ground. “There is a lot of acrimony at the constituency level. The cadre is not willing to accept them and that is causing problems as works are also not getting done,” said a Congress leader.

To stem the exodus, minister Krishna Rao met the MLAs. There will also be a full-fledged meeting to sort out all the issues.

TPCC president

The term of Revanth Reddy as president of the Telangana Pradesh Congress Committee (TPCC) has come to an end. A new president is to be appointed. CM Revanth Reddy has made it clear that he would not want to continue as president of TPCC. The frontrunners for the post are Madhu Yaskhi Goud, B Mahesh Kumar Goud, Jagga Reddy and others. A senior Congress leader said, “Representations have been sent to the high command in Delhi. The decision will be taken soon. The contention is to give the post to a candidate from backward classes.”

The president of TPCC is important to conducting activities of the party and dealing with these issues that are cropping up with the party cadre and leadership at the ground level.</text><top_image>https://newsmeter.in/h-upload/2024/08/02/378458-new-project-50.webp</top_image><link>https://newsmeter.in/politics/gadwal-mla-ghar-wapsi-on-hold-mohan-reddy-gets-cm-revanths-support-733486</link></article><article><title>Bathukamma: Hyderabad Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi booked for causing noise pollution, disturbance</title><authors>Newsmeter Network</authors><publish_date>2024-10-14</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: Police have registered a case against Hyderabad Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi for violating the permission clause for the Bathukamma event and causing disturbance by playing loud music at NBT Nagar in Banjara Hills.

According to the Banjara Hills police, the incident occurred on October 10 during the Bathukamma festival. Mayor Vijayalakshmi was the chief guest at the event.

Police officers patrolling the area arrived at the event around 11:30 PM, as the permission was only valid until 10:00 PM.

A police constable reportedly requested the event organizers to stop the music due to concerns over noise pollution. However, Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi allegedly approached the constable, insisting that the police should not interfere and allow the event to continue with high-decibel music.

Despite the police's intervention, efforts were made to continue the event, leading to a significant disturbance in the neighborhood.

As a result, the Banjara Hills police registered a case against the event organizers, Kandadi Vijay Kumar and Mohd Ghouse, as well as Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi. They have been booked for violating noise pollution regulations under section 223, 280, 292, 49 r/w 3(5) BNS, and Sec 21/76 of the CP Act.</text><top_image>https://newsmeter.in/h-upload/2024/10/14/384447-img-20241013-wa0041.webp</top_image><link>https://newsmeter.in/hyderabad/bathukamma-hyderabad-mayor-gadwal-vijayalakshmi-booked-for-causing-noise-pollution-disturbance-737346</link></article><article><title>Timmar Mallanna to Address Concerns Over Minor Girl's Death in Gadwal.</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-10-28</publish_date><text>Gadwal : Timmar Mallanna, the Member of Legislative Council (MLC), has expressed serious concern over the recent death of a minor girl from the BC community, Rajeshwari, belonging to the Vaddera social group, in the Mallakhal mandal of Jogulamba Gadwal district. Timmar Mallanna is scheduled to visit the girl’s family on October 30th to offer condolences.

On Monday, Timmar Mallanna's team, including state committee member M. Shiva Veer, visited Rajeshwari's native village, Bijwaram, along with Praveen Raj, the president of the Timmar Mallanna team in Gadwal district. They met with Rajeshwari's mother to express their condolences. Congress party constituency in-charge Sarita Tirupathiah also visited the family. During their visit, they demanded the arrest and strict punishment of Bandla Rajasekhar Reddy, a worker linked to the incident leading to Rajeshwari’s death. They further demanded the provision of a double bedroom house and an ex-gratia payment of 50 lakhs to the family.

Members of the Timmar Mallanna team from Narayanpet district, including Venkata Reddy and Vijay Kumar Goud, and co-convenor of the Jogulamba Gadwal district team, Neela Narsinglu, along with Maladkal mandal convenor Thirumala, and other leaders from the Akhilapaksham, also participated in the visit.

A significant tribute was paid in Maladkal mandal under the leadership of the Nadigadda Rights Struggle Committee, demanding legal action against Bandla Rajasekhar Reddy for the death of Rajeshwari. The committee called for immediate action and the arrest of the accused in connection with her death.

This call was echoed in several villages including Salakapura, Aluru, and Nagar Doddipalli, where locals gathered to pay their respects and demanded justice for Rajeshwari. The Nadigadda Rights Struggle Committee organized these tributes, emphasizing the need for legal measures against Bandla Rajasekhar Reddy for his alleged role in the tragic incident.

The situation has drawn significant attention, and local leaders are urging swift action to address the concerns surrounding the circumstances of Rajeshwari’s death.























































</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/28/1492827-untitled-1.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/timmar-mallanna-to-address-concerns-over-minor-girls-death-in-gadwal-917711</link></article><article><title>Jogulamba Gadwal Police Rank 5th in State for Mobile Recovery through CEIR Portal</title><authors>M Veeresh Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-11-06</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Jogulamba Gadwal District Ranks 5th in the State for Mobile Recovery through CEIR Portal State DGP Dr. Jitender, IPS, Commends the Police Force

The Jogulamba Gadwal District Police have shown exemplary performance in recovering stolen and lost mobile phones, earning recognition from Telangana State DGP Dr. Jitender, IPS, who presented them with a Certificate of Appreciation on Tuesday. From April 2023 to October 2024, the district police identified and recovered 948 mobile phones and returned them to their rightful owners. In recognition of this achievement, DGP Dr. Jitender, IPS, praised District SP T. Srinivas Rao, IPS, along with district police officers and staff. The Certificate of Appreciation was handed over to IT Cell in-charge SI Smt. Rajitha by the DGP.

On this occasion, the District SP highlighted the efforts to curb mobile theft by utilizing the Department of Telecommunications’ CEIR (Central Equipment Identity Register) portal, which has yielded excellent results. SP Srinivas Rao urged the public to promptly report lost or stolen mobiles by blocking them on the CEIR portal and notifying the relevant police station. SP Srinivas Rao commended the district police team for their efforts, which have secured Jogulamba Gadwal District the 5th position in mobile recovery across the state.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/11/06/1494781-ceir.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/jogulamba-gadwal-police-rank-5th-in-state-for-mobile-recovery-through-ceir-portal-919451</link></article><article><title>Drone Survey Launched for Comprehensive Master Plan in Gadwal Municipality</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-10-29</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Gadwal District Collector B.M. Santosh announced that a master plan for Gadwal Municipality is underway through a comprehensive drone survey.

On Tuesday, in the premises of the Collectorate, the drone was inaugurated by Municipal Chairperson B.S. Keshavalu along with municipal officials and Survey of India officers under the supervision of DTCP (Directorate of Town and Country Planning) officials. The inauguration included a ceremonial puja to mark the launch of the drone survey initiative.

During the event, the District Collector emphasized that this master plan is part of a larger development initiative aimed at addressing municipal challenges and ensuring the city’s infrastructure is well-planned for future generations. He stated that the goal is to make the information available in digital form for future reference. As part of the central government’s AMRUT 2.0 scheme, Gadwal is among 20 selected municipalities in Telangana where GIS-based planning is being implemented through digital master surveys.

Collector Santosh explained that the Gadwal master plan would be developed using the latest technology and detailed drone camera surveys. The data will be collected section-wise, creating base maps with comprehensive visual documentation. The precise mapping gathered through drone surveys will allow for an in-depth analysis of buildings, roads, water resources, parks, and sewage systems, facilitating maintenance and development through integrated planning.

The collector and team reviewed the drone survey process on a computer, learning how the drone covers the entire municipality, processes the collected data, and how to utilize the survey’s insights. The collector expressed confidence that this digital master plan survey would significantly contribute to the development of Gadwal town.

The program saw the participation of DTCP Additional Director Ramesh Babu, Municipal Commissioner Dasharath, Town Planning Officer Kurmanna, officials from the Survey of India, DTCP officials, and municipal staff.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/29/1493126-drone.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/drone-survey-launched-for-comprehensive-master-plan-in-gadwal-municipality-917962</link></article><article><title>Ghar Wapsi: Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy quits Congress, rejoins BRS</title><authors>Telangana Today</authors><publish_date>2024-07-30</publish_date><text>Ghar Wapsi: Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy quits Congress, rejoins BRS

The Gadwal MLA met BRS working president KT Rama Rao at the party legislative office on the Assembly premises and expressed his desire to rejoin the party.

By Telangana Today Published Date - 30 July 2024, 03:07 PM

Hyderabad: In a fresh twist to the Congress attempts to poach the BRS MLAs, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy who joined the ruling party recently, chose to return to the opposition again. Incidentally, he declared his decision even as the Congress was busy celebrating release of the second tranche of farm loan waiver amount at the Assembly premises.

The Gadwal MLA met BRS working president KT Rama Rao at the party legislative office on the Assembly premises and expressed his desire to rejoin the party. The meeting visuals went viral on the social media, with the BRS official handle posting them on X, asking the media to write “BRS Debba, Congress Abba (BRS shocker to Congress).”

During his meeting with Rama Rao, Krishna Mohan Reddy requested permission for “Ghar Wapsi” (homecoming), which was accepted. BRS leaders expressed hope that a majority of the nine other MLAs who had switched loyalties to the ruling Congress would also return to the BRS fold.

He had joined the Congress party on July 6 in the presence of Chief Minister and TPCC President A Revanth Reddy and other leaders. However, he was reportedly unhappy with the party and regretted his decision.</text><top_image>https://media.telanganatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Bandla-Krishna-Mohan-Reddy.jpg</top_image><link>https://telanganatoday.com/ghar-wapsi-gadwal-mla-krishna-mohan-reddy-quits-congress-rejoins-brs</link></article><article><title>Congress leaders meet GHMC mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi to invite her to join the party</title><authors>Authors</authors><publish_date>2024-03-22</publish_date><text>In another setback to the Bharat Rashtra Samiti (BRS), the Greater Hyderabad Municipal Corporation (GHMC) Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi is likely to switch over to the Congress.

The All India Congress Committee (AICC) in-charge for Telangana, Deepa Das Munshi, Advisor to Government, Vem Narender Reddy and DCC Khairatabad president, Rohin Reddy met the Mayor at her residence and invited her to the Congress party.

The one-hour long meeting also saw the presence of BRS Parliamentary party leader in Rajya Sabha K. Keshava Rao. Ms. Vijayalakshmi is the daughter of Mr. Keshava Rao.

Sources said the the Mayor was invited into the Congress and though she gave enough hints of considering their request positively, she had sought some more time. She had met Telangana Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy in the first week of February this year and claimed it was a courtesy call and she was with the BRS.

GHMC mayor @GadwalvijayaTRS who met with CM Revanth said that she is not shifting parties &amp; will remain with BRS



She has requested him to take action regarding

✴️GHMC Standing Council Committee

✴️General Body meeting

✴️GHMC budget introduction



The CM holds MA&amp;UD portfolio too https://t.co/xhQ1vEpR9Tpic.twitter.com/HfmpyHgQEG — The Hindu-Hyderabad (@THHyderabad) February 3, 2024

However, the political situation in Hyderabad seems to be changing at a pretty rapid pace. The BRS party has already seen some defections and many more are likely to desert it as the election season picks up.

Among the list of BRS leaders who joined Congress include the Deputy Mayor of Greater Hyderabad Municipal Corporation (GHMC), Mothe Srilatha Reddy. She joined the party along with her husband and senior BRS leader Shobhan Reddy.

Also, the former mayor of GHMC, Bonthu Rammohan and former deputy Mayor Baba Fasiuddin, who were with BRS, joined Congress in February.</text><top_image>https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/900qg7/article67980169.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/10504_11_2_2021_19_6_0_1_DSC_8877.JPG</top_image><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/flutter-in-brs-as-aicc-telangana-in-charge-meets-mayor-gadwal-vijayalakshmi/article67979918.ece</link></article><article><title>Gadwal woman delivers baby girl in RTC bus while going to tie rakhi</title><authors>M Srinivas, Sanjay Samuel Paul, About The Author</authors><publish_date>2024-08-19</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: Conductor G. Bharti of Gadwal TGSRTC depot helped Sandhya, a pregnant woman from Gadwal, to deliver a baby in the Pelle Velugu bus they were travelling on Monday.

Sandhya was on her way to Wanaparthy to tie rakhi to her brothers on the occasion of Raksha bandhan.

As soon as the bus reached Nachanahalli, the pregnant woman suffered labour pains. Bharati, who was immediately alerted, stopped the bus. She and a nurse, who was also traveling in the bus, helped Sandhya to deliver a girl. Later, the mother and child were taken to a local hospital, the TGSRTC management said in a release adding that the two were safe and healthy.

Meanwhile, transport minister Ponnam Prabakhar and the RTC management appreciated the efforts of the conductor for her promptness. She demonstrated that spirit of service was a social responsibility, they said.



In an earlier instance on June 19, a pregnant woman was waiting at Karimnagar depot for a bus to Bhadrachalam, when she developed severe labour pains. The RTC staff helped her deliver in the depot. On July 5, one pregnant woman, Swetha Ratnam boarded a bus at Aramghar in the city. When the bus reached Bhadurpura, she complained of labour pains. The conductor stopped the bus and along with the other women passengers, she delivered a healthy child.</text><top_image>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2024/08/19/1832001-untitleddesign13.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/gadwal-woman-delivers-baby-girl-in-rtc-bus-while-going-to-tie-rakhi-1817471</link></article><article><title>GHMC Mayor seeks ₹10,500 crore from 16th Finance Commission</title><authors>Authors</authors><publish_date>2024-09-10</publish_date><text>Greater Hyderabad Municipal Corporation (GHMC) mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi has made a pitch for allocation of ₹10,500 crore for development of Hyderabad, to the 16th Finance Commission which is currently on a tour of the city and Telangana.

She has submitted a representation to the chairman of the commission Arvind Panagariya on Monday (September 9, 2024), during the meeting with political party representatives.

For the period of the 16th Finance Commission’s recommendations, which would start from April 1, 2026, the Mayor sought ₹7,500 crore for providing ‘world class’ infrastructure in the city which comprises road upgradation, comprehensive maintenance of roads, strengthening of stormwater drains, addressing traffic issues and reduction of air pollution, besides mitigation of urban flooding.

Allocation of ₹1,500 crore was requested for bioremediation and biomining of the legacy dump sites and ground and surface water remediation at the legacy dump sites. Besides, ₹800 crore was sought for preservation of lakes, and management of urban flooding in the city, and ₹250 crore each for GIS mapping of the city for execution of Master Plan and for AI-based traffic management system. Allocation of ₹200 crore was for preservation of heritage structures.

The Greater Hyderabad Municipal Corporation has spent about ₹18,000 crore as capital expenditure (₹6,000 crore as loans) during the past 10 years, and will need same amount of funds for the coming five years, as per the representation.

Though the nature and scope of services to be provided by the GHMC are very broad, the 15th Finance Commission had recommended grant only for two components, namely Solid Waste Management and National Clean Air Programme, as per the letter.</text><top_image>https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/cities/Hyderabad/aomty/article68625109.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/GHMC%20Mayor%20at%2016th%20Finance%20Commission.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Hyderabad/ghmc-mayor-seeks-10500-crore-from-16th-finance-commission/article68622944.ece</link></article><article><title>Tackling illegal mining with an iron hand</title><authors>The Hans India</authors><publish_date>2024-07-05</publish_date><text>Gadwal : During his student days, Krishna mohan Reddy played an active part in Akhil Bharatiya Vidyarthi Parishad and fought against illegal mining on a large scale. Later, he joined the Telugu Desam Party and began his political career.

Krishnamohan Reddy was born on September 21, 1967, to Venkataram Reddy and Revathamma in Bureddypally village of Jogulamba Gadwal district. Hailing from a poor farmer’s family, he completed his Class X from Government High School, Gadwal in 1982 and Intermediate from Government Junior College, Atmakur in 1988. Krishnamohan Reddy ventured into business for a while.

In 2009, he was defeated by Congress candidate DK Aruna. In 2014, he contested as a Telangana Rashtra Samithi (TRS) party candidate and lost to the Congress candidate DK Aruna by a margin of 8,260 votes.

In 2017, he was appointed as the TRS party secretary. Krishnamohan Reddy contested on TRS ticket in the 2018 election and won against the nearest Congress candidate, DK Aruna, with a majority of 51,687 votes. On January 26, 2022, he was appointed as the president of the TRS party, Jogulamba Gadwal district. He has been announced as the BRS MLA candidate from Gadwal in the 2023 assembly elections, and was re-elected as an MLA.

Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy was praised by the former chief minister K Chandrashekar Rao as a dynamic leader and a fighter against illegal mining. Currently, there is a huge buzz in social media of him switching over to the Congress party.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/07/05/1459657-untitled-1.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/tackling-illegal-mining-with-an-iron-hand-889493</link></article><article><title>Gadwal MLA Continues in Congress Party Minister Ju Palli Confirms</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-08-01</publish_date><text>Gadwal: A press meet was held today at the MLA camp office in Gadwal district, attended by Minister Jupally Krishna Rao, Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy, and Devarakadra MLA G. Madhusudan Reddy, addressing the recent rumors about party changes.

Minister's Statement

Minister Jupally Krishna Rao clarified that the news circulating in major newspapers, media, and social media about the MLA switching parties is false. He emphasized that speaking with acquaintances in the Assembly lobbies does not imply that MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy has left the Congress party to join the BRS party.

Minister Jupally reiterated that MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy will continue with the Congress party, stating that he joined the party from the BRS solely for the development of the Gadwal constituency.

On July 30, MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy met KTR in a friendly manner. The rumors about him leaving Congress to join BRS are baseless.

Minister Jupally Krishna Rao assured that the government is committed to the development of the region as requested by the Gadwal MLA, and Krishna Mohan Reddy has joined the Congress party with this commitment in mind.

Accompanied by Minister Jupally Krishna Rao, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy departed for the Assembly.

The event was attended by public representatives, senior Congress leaders, and party workers.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/08/01/1467342-mla.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/gadwal-mla-continues-in-congress-party-minister-ju-palli-confirms-896218</link></article><article><title>Jogulamba Gadwal District Must Lead in Every Health Program: DMHO Dr. Siddappa</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-10-04</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Today, a review meeting was held at the Jogulamba Gadwal District Medical and Health Department office, led by District Medical and Health Officer (DMHO) Dr. Siddappa. Addressing various Primary Health Center (PHC) supervisors, Dr. Siddappa emphasized the importance of each PHC being at the forefront of all health programs in the district.



He highlighted the crucial role of supervisors in these initiatives, urging them to be aware of targets and achievements in advance, and to work closely with their staff. He recommended holding a "part night" meeting every 15 days to review progress and stressed the need to increase the number of deliveries in government hospitals while reducing private deliveries.

The review meeting was attended by District Program Officers Dr. Sandhya Kiran Mai, Dr. Naveen Kumar Reddy, Dr. G. Raju, and Dr. Prasoonarani, along with district medical staff including DDM Ramu, ASO Tirumalesh Reddy, District NCD Coordinator Shyamsunder, and various PHC supervisors.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/04/1486369-whatsapp-image-2024-10-04-at-72915-pm.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/jogulamba-gadwal-district-must-lead-in-every-health-program-dmho-dr-siddappa-912121</link></article><article><title>Bharosa centres inaugurated at Mahabubnagar, Jogulamba Gadwal districts</title><authors>Telangana Today</authors><publish_date>2024-11-12</publish_date><text>Bharosa centres inaugurated at Mahabubnagar, Jogulamba Gadwal districts

These centres will provide assistance to victims of crime against women and children through dedicated single-window support centres

By Telangana Today Published Date - 12 November 2024, 07:17 PM

Hyderabad: Two Bharosa centres were inaugurated at Mahabubnagar and Jogulamba Gadwal districts in the State on Tuesday.

These centres will provide assistance to victims of crime against women and children through dedicated single-window support centres. “The services offered to survivors include counselling, legal aid, medical assistance, rehabilitation and other essential services,” said DG Women Safety Wing, Shikha Goel.

Since May 2016, Telangana police has started 27 Bharosa centres across the State. In the first half of this year, 14 new centres were inaugurated in Jagityal, Bhadradri Kothagudem, Jangaon, Mancheriyal, Mulugu, Nagarkurnool, Peddapally, Jayashanker Bhupalpally, Kamareddy, Rajanna Sircilla, Kumarambheem Asifabad, Narayanpet, Nirmal and Wanaparthy.

Shikha Goel said Bharosa centres, managed by Bharosa – Society for Protection of Women and Children- offer specialized support for victims. Each centre, staffed with professionals including counsellors, psychologists, legal officers, and medical personnel, ensures comprehensive care.

“The vision also encompasses addressing modern crimes against women and children, with every centre having a woman police officer and medical officer for holistic assistance,” said the official.

Since inception, these centres have aided 5,852 related to Protection of Children from Sexual Offenses (POCSO) and 1447 rape cases, demonstrating their pivotal role in enabling justice and rehabilitation.</text><top_image>https://media.telanganatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bharosa.jpg</top_image><link>https://telanganatoday.com/bharosa-centres-inaugurated-at-mahabubnagar-jogulamba-gadwal-districts</link></article><article><title>Mission Bhagiratha Pipeline Leaks, Wasting Water in Gadwal District</title><authors>Fouzia Farhana</authors><publish_date>2024-11-15</publish_date><text>Gadwal: A significant incident of water wastage has occurred in Gadwal district, where a section of the Mission Bhagiratha pipeline has burst, resulting in large amounts of water flowing wastefully into the open. The pipeline ruptured near Kothula Gidda Stage in Dharur Mandal, causing a visible spill of water that could have been better utilized.

Mission Bhagiratha Pipeline Burst

The pipeline, part of the Mission Bhagiratha project aimed at providing safe drinking water to rural areas across Telangana, suffered a major rupture, leading to water gushing out in a steady stream. Locals have expressed concerns about the damage and the environmental impact of the water loss.

Also Read: Confidential Family Survey Documents Found Discarded on Road in Medchal

“Water is a precious resource, and it is disheartening to see so much of it being wasted due to such technical failures. The government needs to address these issues immediately,” said a resident of the area.

Impact on Water Supply and Local Communities

The Mission Bhagiratha project, launched by the Telangana government, is intended to supply drinking water to rural areas, but incidents like this pipeline burst raise questions about the reliability and maintenance of the infrastructure. While the pipeline rupture has been quickly reported, immediate repairs are necessary to prevent further wastage and disruption in water supply.

The rupture has also affected the nearby localities that depend on the water supply for daily use. Locals have urged authorities to address the problem urgently to restore water access.

Government Response and Repairs Underway

Officials from the Telangana Drinking Water Supply and Sanitation Department (TDWSSD) have been alerted about the situation, and repair work has reportedly begun. The government has committed to resolving the issue swiftly to ensure that residents of Dharur Mandal and surrounding areas continue to receive their regular water supply.

“We are aware of the leak in the Mission Bhagiratha pipeline near Kothula Gidda and are taking immediate steps to repair the damage. Our teams are on the ground to fix the issue and prevent further wastage,” said a government official.

Call for Better Maintenance and Infrastructure Upgrades

The incident has sparked concerns about the overall maintenance and longevity of the Mission Bhagiratha pipeline network, especially as the state pushes forward with water supply projects in rural areas. Experts have stressed the need for regular inspections and timely repairs to avoid such issues in the future.

With water conservation becoming an urgent priority in many regions, ensuring the efficiency of large-scale water supply projects like Mission Bhagiratha is essential for meeting the needs of rural communities across Telangana.

Conclusion

While the pipeline burst in Gadwal district highlights the challenges of maintaining vast infrastructure projects, the Telangana government’s quick response aims to minimize the damage. As work on repairs continues, authorities are working to ensure that the water wastage is stopped and that the supply remains uninterrupted for the affected communities.</text><top_image>https://2c31032a.delivery.rocketcdn.me/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/WATERWASTE.jpg</top_image><link>https://munsifdaily.com/mission-bhagiratha-pipeline-leaks-wasting-water-in-gadwal-district/</link></article><article><title>Gadwal: BRS netas lead farmers’ protests</title><authors>The Hans India</authors><publish_date>2024-10-21</publish_date><text>Gadwal: In a show of protest across the Gadwal constituency, the Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) party has demanded a public apology from Revanth Reddy for allegedly failing to keep the promises made to farmers. This demand follows the remarks made by Agriculture Minister Tummala Nageswara Rao, who stated that the government could not provide the promised “Raitu Bharosa” (Farmer’s Assurance) to farmers.

In response to the call of, BRS Working President K T Rama Rao, farmers came out on streets and held protests in various mandals, including Gattu, Maldakal, and K.T. Doddi. Local leaders like Basu Hanumanth Naidu organized the demonstrations. Which saw the activists attempt to set effigies of the state government on fire. However, the police intervened to stop the effigy burning in several mandal centers, leading to tensions between the police and

BRS leaders.

Among those who took part in the protests were Jayasimha Reddy, Venkatesh, Timmappa Goud, S Ramu, Raju Naidu, and others. They said they would fight for the cause of farmers until the government concedes the farmers’ demands.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/21/1490769-gadwal.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/gadwal-brs-netas-lead-farmers-protests-915870</link></article><article><title>Telangana DSC 2024 Ranks: Jogulamba Gadwal District Rankers List</title><authors /><publish_date /><text>The DSC exams for a total of 11,062 posts were conducted online from July 18 to August 5.

Download TS DSC Notification 2023: District-wise SGT, SA Vacancies List https://education.sakshi.com/en/dsc/education-news/ts-dsc-notification-2023-district-wise-sgt-sa-vacancies-list-137995</text><top_image>https://education.sakshi.com/sites/default/files/styles/lead_vertical_lead/public/images/2024/10/05/tsdsc244-1728105348.jpg</top_image><link>https://education.sakshi.com/en/dsc/education-news/telangana-dsc-2024-ranks-jogulamba-gadwal-district-rankers-list-164797</link></article><article><title>GHMC Mayor orders shut down of chicken market in Hyderabad’s Esamiya Bazaar</title><authors>News Desk</authors><publish_date>2024-11-22</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: APC chicken market in Hyderabad’s New Moti Nagar was raided by Greater Hyderabad Municipal Corporation (GHMC) Mayor Gadwal Vijayalaxmi on Friday, November 22. Following the raid, the Mayor ordered a temporary closure of the market, citing severe hygiene violations.

The Mayor was accompanied by MLC Balmuri Venkat, on her surprise visit to the chicken market in Esamiya Bazaar, New Moti Nagar, Koti.

The Greater Hyderabad Mayor found a staunch smell reeking from the chicken market, and meat being kept for sale in highly unhygienic conditions. She also took note of compliance with quality standards and legality.

Enraged by the findings, the Mayor ordered to temporarily seal off the wholesale chicken market, by directing the zonal commissioner to initiate the proceedings immediately.

The neighbourhood’s medical officer was ordered by the GHMC Mayor to clean all the surrounding areas in coordination with the entomology and sanitation officers.

GHMC Mayor raids restaurants in Hyderabad

Last week, GHMC Mayor Vijayalaxmi conducted surprise inspections at two popular restaurants in the city. During the inspections at Mughal Restaurant in Lakdikapul and Dine Hill Hotel in Masab Tank, violations were found, prompting her to issue a strong warning to restaurant and hotel owners.

The Mayor reminded the restaurant management that strict measures would be enforced against establishments that fail to meet hygiene standards.

Additionally, she announced that any hotels or restaurants operating without proper food and trade licenses would face immediate penalties, including possible shutdowns.

GHMC has recently ramped up measures to improve food hygiene in the city, with the corporation officials and district authorities also conducting awareness campaigns to educate food vendors and raids across eateries in Hyderabad and other parts of Telangana. Street vendors participating in these initiatives are provided with free hygiene kits, including aprons, head caps, and gloves, to encourage safe food handling practices.

Despite ongoing efforts by Hyderabad’s food safety teams, violations continue to be found in some restaurants in Hyderabad. These inspections are part of a broader initiative to maintain the quality and cleanliness of food provided to the public.

By holding restaurants accountable, the Mayor aims to reassure citizens that the city is committed to improving dining conditions across Hyderabad.</text><top_image>https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/APC-Chicken-Market-in-Hyderabad-raided-by-GHMC-Mayor.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.siasat.com/ghmc-mayor-orders-shut-down-of-chicken-market-in-hyderabad-esamiya-bazaar-3135781/</link></article><article><title>Gadwal: Five nabbed for online betting</title><authors>The Hans India</authors><publish_date>2024-11-05</publish_date><text>Gadwal: The Aija police have arrested five individuals for engaging in online betting. This operation was initiated following information received by the Special Branch police. Acting on the orders of District SP T Srinivasa Rao, and under the supervision of Special Branch Inspector Nageshwar Reddy, a joint team led by Ijay Sub-Inspector Vijay Bhaskar monitored the situation.

During the operation, the police identified the individuals involved in online betting, seizing cash amounting to Rs 1,04,860 and five mobile phones from them. Subsequently, a case was registered against the accused at the Ijay police station by SI Vijay Bhaskar.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/30/1493257-arrest.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/gadwal-five-nabbed-for-online-betting-919221</link></article><article><title>Defected Gadwal MLA Bandla Makes a BRS Ghar Wapsi</title><authors>Dc Correspondent, About The Author</authors><publish_date>2024-07-31</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: In a surprising turn of events, Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy, MLA from Gadwal constituency, rejoined the BRS just days after defecting to the ruling Congress party on Tuesday.

Reddy, who had left the party on July 6, surfaced at the BRS Legislature Party chambers in the Legislative Assembly premises and met BRS working president K.T. Rama Rao to express his desire to return to the party fold.

Party sources said that Rama Rao immediately called up his father and BRS chief K. Chandrashekar Rao and sought his approval. Chandrashekar Rao reportedly gave his nod following which Reddy rejoined the party, BRS leaders claimed.

Speculations were rife in BRS circles that three more party MLAs, who had defected to the Congress, including Kale Yadaiah (Chevella), Gudem Mahipal Reddy (Patancheru) and Tellam Venkat Rao (Bhadrachalam) are in contact with BRS leadership and are willing to rejoin BRS.

The reasons behind Krishna Mohan's swift change of allegiance are not immediately clear. However, it has been reported that he felt uncomfortable within the Congress ranks. Notably, Congress workers from the Gadwal constituency had expressed opposition to his entry into their party, adding to the complexity of the situation.

The return of Krishna Mohan is a notable development for BRS as it provides some relief, following the series of defections. Since March, BRS has lost ten MLAs, six MLCs, and several senior leaders to Congress. This includes a major setback in the Secunderabad Cantonment Assembly by-election, where its candidate was defeated by Congress, reducing its strength in the Assembly.

With Krishna Mohan's re-entry, BRS hopes to stabilise its position in the state Assembly. The party, which initially secured 39 seats in the 119-member House, saw its numbers dwindle to 28 due to defections and electoral losses.

Meanwhile, the Congress party's strength increased to 72 seats, bolstered by the recent influx of BRS MLAs.

In a different development, BRS Medchal MLA Ch. Malla Reddy went to the CLP office in the Assembly and met Deputy Chief Minister Mallu Bhatti Vikramarka on Tuesday. This fuelled speculations about a possible switching of loyalties. However, later Malla Reddy clarified that he had met Vikramarka to seek funds for his constituency and there was no other political significance.

Meanwhile, a picture of Bhadrachalam BRS MLA Tellam Venkat Rao, who defected to Congress, having a conversation with BRS MLAs in the

assembly lobby on Tuesday went viral on social media and fuelled speculations of his 'ghar wapsi'. However, Tellam said that there was no truth in the rumours. “It is not right to spread such rumours against me. It is not right to send pictures of me having tea with BRS MLAs in the Assembly lobby,” Rao said.

Making light of this incident, minister Komatireddy Venkat Reddy said that the media had blown the issue out of proportion. "Where did Krishna Mohan say that he is rejoining BRS? Did he tell the media about this? BRS leaders are spreading lies on this."

Congress MLA Yennam Srinivas Reddy also denied reports that Krishna Mohan was ill-treated in the Congress.

"We have given him due importance. He is facing some issues in his constituency with Congress leaders and former Gadwal zilla parishad chairperson Saritha, who contested against him in the Assembly polls. That could be the reason for his disappointment."</text><top_image>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2024/07/30/1827731-ktr.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/defected-gadwal-mla-bandla-makes-a-brs-ghar-wapsi-1813380</link></article><article><title>Telangana: Crocodile enters cotton fields in Gadwal, rescued</title><authors>News Desk</authors><publish_date>2024-08-24</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: Farmers in Maldakal mandal headquarters of Jogulamba Gadwal district were shocked to see a crocodile entering the seed cotton field of a farmer near Devaracheruvu.

The farm workers who were busy with their work in the cotton fields, were shocked to see a crocodile crawling in the field on the morning of Friday, August 23. The workers immediately informed the police and forest officials.

A crocodile which entered a cotton field in Maldakal mandal of Gadwal district was rescued and released back into Krishna River by forest officials on Friday. @TheSiasat pic.twitter.com/N0Ib8ESaGE — Vivek Bhoomi (@Vivek_bhoomi) August 23, 2024

Zamindar Purender, constable Niranjan and forest staff who reached the spot immediately, caught the crocodile with the help of farmers.

The crocodile was released into the irrigation tank. It is suspected that the crocodile may have entered the farm, as the minor irrigation tanks were overflowing due to heavy rains.</text><top_image>https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/forest-officials-rescue-crocodile-Gadwal.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.siasat.com/telangana-crocodile-enters-cotton-fields-in-gadwal-rescued-3083965/</link></article><article><title>Minister Jupally faces ire of Congress workers over Gadwal BRS MLA defection to party</title><authors>Telangana Today</authors><publish_date>2024-08-17</publish_date><text>Minister Jupally faces ire of Congress workers over Gadwal BRS MLA defection to party

Tension escalated in the town soon after Jupally Krishna Rao reached Gadwal. Holding Congress party flags and raising slogans, Sarita's supporters squatted in front of the convoy.

By Telangana Today Updated On - 17 August 2024, 02:54 PM

Jogulamba Gadwal: Internal bickerings in the Congress in Gadwal constituency peaked to such an extent that Congress workers and followers Sarita Tirupataiah, who lost her election in the last assembly elections as a Congress candidate, prevented the Tourism Minister Jupally Krishna Rao from attending an official programme.

The workers were demanding that the minister pay a visit to Sarita’s house first before going to the official programme along with the local MLA Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy.

The rivalry between Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy and Sarita had been going on for a while, with Reddy, who won on a BRS ticket against Sarita later defected to the Congress much to the chagrin of Sarita and her followers.

On Saturday Reddy was accompanying the minister when Sarita’s followers obstructed the convoy and argued with Jupally Krishna Rao that he should visit Sarita’s house first and then proceed to inspect reservoirs and water bodies in the district.

Tension escalated in the town soon after the Minister reached Gadwal. Holding Congress party flags and raising slogans, Sarita’s supporters squatted in front of the convoy.

The minister and his associates tried in vain to convince Sarita’s followers to allow the minsiter to go with the assurance that he would stop at her house while returning. However, so incensed were the Congress workers that they raised “Jupally down down” slogans. The minister’s repeated assurances that he would call on her in his return journey fell on deaf ears.

As the situation was turning worse, the Minister’s followers convinced him to visit Saritha Tirupataiah’s residence first. Heeding to their requests, he went to Sarita’s residence first and then proceeded to attend his official programmes.

The stiff opposition by Congress leaders over the entry of BRS MLAs into the Congress has been continuing. Krishnamohan Reddy had defected to the Congress and then later expressed his willingness to join the BRS again, but within a day changed his mind again to stick with the Congress.</text><top_image>https://media.telanganatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/jupally.jpg</top_image><link>https://telanganatoday.com/minister-jupally-faces-ire-of-congress-workers-over-gadwal-brs-mla-defection-to-party</link></article><article><title>MLA Bandla met CM Revanth to emphasize about the development of irrigation schemes</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-07-15</publish_date><text>Gadwal: On Monday Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy, MLA of Gadwal met with Chief Minister Revanth Reddy at the CM's camp office in Hyderabad to discuss several crucial development projects in his constituency.

During the meeting, Mr. Reddy emphasized the urgent need to increase the water capacity of the Nettempadu and Ryalam padu projects within the Gadwal constituency. He proposed the release of funds for the construction of an embankment raising scheme, which is vital to enhance the water storage capabilities of these reservoirs.

Additionally, Mr. Reddy requested the Chief Minister to allocate funds for the completion of the pending development works associated with the Priyadarshini Jurala Project. This project, which has been delayed for some time, requires immediate financial support to ensure its successful completion and the benefits it promises to the local communities.

Mr. Reddy submitted a detailed petition outlining various development works that need immediate attention and funding. He urged CM Revanth Reddy to prioritize the release of these funds, emphasizing that completing these projects is essential for the overall development and prosperity of the Gadwal constituency.

In response, Chief Minister Revanth Reddy assured Mr. Reddy of his commitment to addressing these issues. He acknowledged the importance of the proposed projects and the need for timely completion of the pending works. The Chief Minister promised to expedite the release of funds and support the development initiatives for the benefit of the Gadwal constituency.

This meeting marks a significant step towards advancing infrastructure and water management projects in Gadwal, highlighting the collaborative efforts between local and state government officials to improve the quality of life for their constituents.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/07/15/1462664-bandla.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/mla-bandla-met-cm-revanth-to-emphasize-about-the-development-of-irrigation-schemes-892196</link></article><article><title>Seventh BRS MLA joins Congress</title><authors>Authors</authors><publish_date>2024-07-06</publish_date><text>Defections from the Bharat Rashtra Samiti (BRS) continued on Saturday with Gadwal MLA, Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy joining Congress in the presence of Chief Minister A Revanth Reddy at his residence in Hyderabad.

The Gadwal MLA is considered close to the BRS working president K.T. Rama Rao and was one of the two BRS candidates to have won from the combined Mahabubnagar district that was swept by the Congress in the 2023 Telangana Assembly elections.

Seventh BRS MLA to join Congress

He is the seventh BRS MLA to have shifted to the Congress. So far six BRS MLAs left the party and they include Kadiyam Srihari,Danam Nagender, Tellam Venkat Rao, Pocharam Srinivas Reddy, Sanjay Kumar and Kale Yadaiah.

Mr. Krishnamohan Reddy’s entry was in the news for the last few days as the local Congress leaders opposed his entry, particularly the former Zilla Parishad chairperson Saritha, who unsuccessfully contested against him in the last Assembly elections and lost narrowly. Ms. Saritha joined the Congress just before the elections from the BRS for a better political career and was a supporter of Mr. Krishnamohan Reddy.

BRS now has just one MLA in the combined Mahabubnagar district, Gattu Bheemudu, who represents the Alampur constituency. Sources said he is also expected to join the Congress soon.

Mr. Krishnamohan Reddy is a nephew of Mahbubnagar MP from the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), DK Aruna, and in fact defeated her in the 2018 Assembly elections when she was in the Congress party. Known to be a hard worker, Mr. Krishnamohan Reddy was one of the few leaders in whom BRS working president KTR had a lot of faith. His personal stature has what helped him to win in Mahbubnagar district that was swept by the Congress in the last elections.

Four more BRS MLAs ready to join

Meanwhile, four more BRS MLAs from the Hyderabad city are expected to join the Congress. Some of these MLAs skipped the party meeting on Friday and they also stayed away from the GHMC Council meeting on Saturday.

The BRS had won 39 seats in the 2023 elections out of the 119. The party’s MLA from Cantonment, Lasya Nanditha, passed away in a road accident in February 2024. In the by-poll held along with the Parliament elections, Congress candidate Sri Ganesh won the seat thus reducing the effective number to 38. Out of these, seven MLAs have left the party so far.</text><top_image>https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/cities/Hyderabad/8vlazg/article68374776.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Gadwal%20MLA%20Bandla%20Krishnamohan%20Reddy%20joins%20Congress%20in%20the%20presence%20of%20Telangana%20Chief%20Minister%20A.%20Revanth%20Reddy%20in%20Hyderabad%20on%20July%206%202024.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/yet-another-brs-mla-joins-congress/article68374214.ece</link></article><article><title>Neeli Srinivasulu Valmiki Sworn in as Jogulamba Gadwal District Library Chairman Amid Grand Celebrations</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-10-18</publish_date><text>Gadwal : A massive rally was held from the District Collectorate to Krishnaveni Junction in Jogulamba Gadwal District to celebrate the swearing-in ceremony of Neeli Srinivasulu Valmiki as the Chairman of the District Library. Thousands of Congress workers enthusiastically participated in the rally.

At Krishnaveni Junction, Minister Ponnam Prabhakar and AICC Secretary Sampath Kumar unveiled a statue of Sardar Sarvai Papanna Goud. The swearing-in ceremony for Neeli Srinivasulu Valmiki as the Library Chairman was conducted by Dr. Riaz, State Library Chairman, in a grand event held at Krishnaveni Junction.

Following the ceremony, Minister Ponnam Prabhakar congratulated Neeli Srinivasulu Valmiki on his appointment. The event was attended by prominent leaders, including Gadwal Congress in-charge Saritha Tirupathayya Yadav, Municipal Chairman B.S. Keshav, Mahbubnagar Municipal Chairman Anand Goud, and other key figures.

Minister Ponnam Prabhakar's Address:

Minister Ponnam Prabhakar extended heartfelt congratulations to Neeli Srinivasulu Valmiki on assuming office as the Library Chairman of Gadwal. He also spoke about the significance of unveiling the statue of Sarvai Papanna Goud, a leader who united people and fought for sovereignty.

Minister Prabhakar emphasized the inspiration that comes from figures like Jyoti Rao Phule and Dr. B.R. Ambedkar, whose lives continue to guide future generations. He highlighted the need for libraries to be utilized by students preparing for competitive exams, expressing the hope that Gadwal would become the leading district in the state in securing jobs.

He also shared the success story of a Dalit becoming the Library Chairman in Siddipet and expressed pride that a Valmiki community leader is now serving as the Chairman in Gadwal.

Minister Prabhakar praised the efforts of the Telangana state government under the leadership of the Honorable Chief Minister in propelling the united Mahbubnagar district towards progress. He mentioned several welfare schemes introduced over the past ten months, such as free travel for women in RTC buses, subsidized cooking gas, free electricity for up to 200 units, and a health insurance scheme covering up to 10 lakh rupees.

Additionally, the government has sanctioned 3,500 Indiramma houses and implemented a 2 lakh rupees loan waiver for farmers. For loans exceeding this amount, the government is offering partial waivers as well.

Minister Prabhakar also addressed the opposition's criticism, urging Congress workers to be prepared to counter negative narratives. He reaffirmed that the government is committed to justice for the SC, ST, BC, and minority communities, as promised by Rahul Gandhi, through the introduction of caste-based census and fair reservation policies.

He concluded by encouraging party members to remain steadfast, stating that the government will work in alignment with their aspirations. Despite the Congress party not being in power for some time, he reflected on his own experience, having stood firm as an NSUI activist and urged others to carry the party's flag forward.



























</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/18/1490086-whatsapp-image-2024-10-18-at-44619-pm-1.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/neeli-srinivasulu-valmiki-sworn-in-as-jogulamba-gadwal-district-library-chairman-amid-grand-celebrations-915343</link></article><article><title>Differences in Gadwal Congress to the fore over Market Yard Committee chairman post</title><authors>Telangana Today</authors><publish_date>2024-08-30</publish_date><text>Differences in Gadwal Congress to the fore over Market Yard Committee chairman post

Ever since BRS MLA B Krishnamohan Reddy defected to Congress, party incharge Saritha Tirupataiah has been locking horns with the former over different issues

By Telangana Today Published Date - 30 August 2024, 11:16 AM

Jogulamba Gadwal: Internal rumblings continue to surface in the district Congress unit. Ever since BRS MLA B Krishnamohan Reddy defected to Congress, the party incharge and former Zilla Parishad Chairperson Saritha Tirupataiah has been locking horns with the former over different issues.

This time, the two groups engaged in a battle over appointment of chairman for Gadwal Market Committee. Both the groups insisting that the person recommended by them should be considered for the appointment. To this effect, both the groups have written letters to the party leadership as well.

Also Read Gadwal Congress leaders up the ante, oppose defection of BRS MLA

While Saritha Tirupataiah recommended the name of Dhanalaxmi for the post, MLA Krishnamohan Reddy referred Kuruva Hanumanthu’s name, according to reports.

These disturbances in the district unit have been posing challenges for the State leadership. The rivalry between the two groups hit a new high on August 17 when Tourism Minister Jupally Krishna Rao experienced a tough time in convincing both groups.

Saritha’s followers blocked the Minister’s convoy and insisted that he pay a visit to her house before participating in the official programmes.

This was after the local MLA joined the Minister for participating in the programmes. As the situation turned tense, the Minister heeded to Saritha’s followers demands and left the local MLA disappointed. These are a few instances, which reflect the plight of the BRS MLAs, who had joined the Congress.</text><top_image>https://media.telanganatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Telangana-Congress.jpg</top_image><link>https://telanganatoday.com/differences-in-gadwal-congress-to-the-fore-over-market-yard-committee-chairman-post</link></article><article><title>Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi Mandates Facial Recognition Attendance for All GHMC Employees</title><authors /><publish_date /><text>Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi Mandates Facial Recognition Attendance for All GHMC Employees

*Hyderabad, November 6* – Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi has declared that all employees of the Greater Hyderabad Municipal Corporation (GHMC) must register for the facial recognition attendance system, underlining that non-compliance will lead to strict disciplinary action against the respective Heads of Departments (HODs). The announcement came after a surprise inspection at the GHMC headquarters, where the Mayor conducted a thorough review of operations across the Town Planning, Health, and Veterinary Departments.



During the inspection, Mayor Vijayalakshmi met with Additional Commissioners and HODs to stress that the use of the facial recognition system is mandatory for all GHMC staff, including permanent and outsourced employees. She made it clear that any failures in implementing this directive would result in consequences for department heads.



A significant focus of the inspection was the reporting of outsourced staff. The Mayor questioned the Additional Commissioner about the exact number of outsourced employees at the GHMC headquarters and noted inconsistencies in reporting. To address this, she instructed officials to submit detailed records verifying the authorization of all outsourced hirings by the Commissioner.



As part of her directive to strengthen administrative oversight, the Mayor mandated that the attendance system should encompass all employees who are on the GHMC payroll, spanning all departments. Future recruitment processes for outsourced personnel are to be conducted solely at the GHMC head office to ensure centralized management and transparency.



Mayor Vijayalakshmi also highlighted the need for a swift and effective response to public grievances. She instructed officials to resolve citizen complaints promptly and to prevent recurrence of the same issues. If a complaint cannot be resolved, officials must provide the applicant with a written explanation. The Mayor warned that failure to adhere to this directive would result in disciplinary action for the respective department heads.



The new measure is aimed at boosting accountability, reducing absenteeism, and ensuring streamlined operations within the GHMC. By implementing facial recognition technology, the GHMC aims to modernize its workforce management and enhance service delivery to the residents of Hyderabad.</text><top_image>https://aimamedia.org/fotos/aimanewsphoto1/_newsphoto1448IMG-20241106-WA0058.jpg</top_image><link>https://aimamedia.org/newsdetails.aspx?nid=346825</link></article><article><title>Mayor booked for allowing music beyond permitted hours in Telangana</title><authors>Express News Service</authors><publish_date>2024-10-14</publish_date><text>HYDERABAD: Banjara Hills police have registered a case against Hyderabad Mayor Gadwal Vijayalaxmi and others for allegedly permitting loud music beyond the allowed hours during a Bathukamma event on Thursday. The event took place at NBT Nagar in Banjara Hills, where organisers reportedly played music well past the permitted time.

The police have registered a case under Sections 223, 280 and 292 of the Bharatiya Nagarik Suraksha Sanhita (BNSS) for disobeying orders issued by public servants, creating a noxious atmosphere harmful to health and causing public nuisance.

A video of the event, widely circulated on social media, shows the mayor standing on a dais, holding a sword, and urging women to wield swords as well. The video drew significant backlash online.

In response to the criticism, the mayor took to X (formerly Twitter) and addressed the incident, stating, “There was an issue concerning women in the area. I assured the women that no one could take advantage of them and that I had been addressing their concerns. I believe there is nothing wrong in standing by them when they need me.”</text><top_image>https://media.assettype.com/newindianexpress%2F2024-07%2F1e84a8f2-693c-41ae-8eb3-e0663c3245fa%2FChao.jpg?w=1200&amp;ar=40%3A21&amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;ogImage=true&amp;mode=crop&amp;enlarge=true&amp;overlay=false&amp;overlay_position=bottom&amp;overlay_width=100</top_image><link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/states/telangana/2024/Oct/14/mayor-booked-for-allowing-music-beyond-permitted-hours-in-telangana</link></article><article><title>Six-year-old boy severely injured in stray dog attack in Gadwal</title><authors>Newstap Bureau</authors><publish_date>2024-10-04</publish_date><text>GADWAL: A six-year-old boy suffered severe injuries following a stray dog attack in Amaravai village, Manavapadu mandal, Jogulamba Gadwal district.

The incident occurred when the body, Revanth, was playing near his home and was suddenly attacked by a stray dog.

Local residents responded quickly, managing to rescue the boy from the dog. Revant sustained multiple injuries in the attack and was immediately rushed to the Kurnool Government Hospital for urgent medical treatment. Doctors at the hospital reported that his condition, though serious, is stable.

The incident has sparked concerns among the residents of Amaravai village regarding the rising number of stray dogs in the area. Several villagers have urged local authorities to take measures to prevent similar incidents in the future, highlighting the need for effective control of the stray dog population.</text><top_image>https://www.newstap.in/h-upload/2024/10/04/1657923-c5f1d713-acb9-49af-b275-977856ce6195.webp</top_image><link>https://www.newstap.in/crime/a-stray-dog-attacked-a-six-year-old-boy-in-amaravai-village-causing-severe-injuries-1553683</link></article><article><title>Justice Demanded for Minor Girl's Death: Nadigadda Rights Struggle Committee Leads Rally in Gadwal</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-10-29</publish_date><text>Gadwal: In a powerful display of solidarity, members of the Nadi gadda Rights Struggle Committee held a large rally to honor Vadde Rajeswari, a minor girl from Bijwaram village in Maldakal Mandal, who died under distressing circumstances. The rally, led by District Chairman Gongalla Ranjith Kumar, began at the Nadi gadda Rights Struggle Committee office and proceeded to the Krishnaveni Chowrasta in Gadwal.

Committee leaders and activists paid tribute to Rajeswari, holding her photograph and lighting candles in her memory.During the event, Chairman Gongalla Ranjith Kumar stated that Rajeswari's death was a tragic result of her inability to cope with the humiliation she faced. Allegedly wrongfully accused of theft, she reportedly ingested pesticide in an attempt to end her life. She later succumbed to the effects of the poison. Ranjith Kumar strongly demanded immediate legal action against prominent seed organizer Bandla Rajasekhar Reddy, whom he claims is responsible for Rajeswari's death. According to Kumar, Rajeswari was wrongfully implicated in a theft case, and despite her repeated denials, police at the Maldakal Police Station continued to pressure her, failing to consider her age or the impact on her family. He alleged that Rajasekhar Reddy, who has avoided arrest, manipulated the system with his political influence to evade accountability.

Ranjith Kumar emphasized that there are multiple layers to the circumstances surrounding Rajeswari's death, calling for an impartial investigation into all angles of the case anddemanding Rajasekhar Reddy's arrest and strict punishment. He announced plans to take the matter to the State DGP soon and warned that the Nadigadda Rights Struggle Committee would intensify its protests across the district if justice is not served for Rajeswari's family. Kumar also called on the government to support the bereaved family.

Several committee members and leaders participated in the event, including District Convenor Bucchibabu, District Secretary Lavanna, poet Avani shree, leaders

Rangaswami and Venkataramulu, Gadwal Mandal leaders Gouni Srinivas Yadav, Karthik, Maldakal Mandal President B. Vishnu, Prem Raj, Gattu Mandal President Balaram Naidu, Dharur Mandal Vice President Adivi Anjaneyulu, K.T. Doddi Mandal leaders Vijay Gajendra, Lakshmanna, Samiyeal, Swamy, Maldakal, and Jammanna.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/29/1493123-gadw.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/justice-demanded-for-minor-girls-death-nadigadda-rights-struggle-committee-leads-rally-in-gadwal-917958</link></article><article><title>ZP ex chair person's Pittetion for development of Gadwal</title><authors>M Veeresh Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-07-12</publish_date><text>Gadwal: In a significant move to accelerate development in the Gadwal constituency, a delegation of Congress party leaders led by former ZP chairperson and Gadwal in-charge Sarita Tirupatiah, along with Nagarkurnool Member of Parliament Mallu Ravi, paid a visit to Telangana State Chief Minister Revanth Reddy at the Hyderabad Secretariat. The meeting, which took place in a warm and collaborative atmosphere, aimed to bring pressing developmental issues to the forefront.

Sarita Tirupatiah and Mallu Ravi, accompanied by senior Congress Party leaders Gattu Krishnamurthy and Dr. Sridhar, began the visit by felicitating Chief Minister Revanth Reddy. The Chief Minister, known for his commitment to regional development, expressed his appreciation for their dedication and welcomed the dialogue on Gadwal's future.

During the meeting, the delegation presented a comprehensive petition outlining the critical areas needing attention in Gadwal. They highlighted infrastructure deficits, emphasizing the need for improved roads, better healthcare facilities, and enhanced educational opportunities. The petition also stressed the urgency of addressing water scarcity and proposed the construction of a dam to support agricultural activities and secure water supply for the region.

Chief Minister Revanth Reddy listened attentively, acknowledging the challenges faced by the Gadwal constituency. He assured the delegation of his support and commitment to resolving these issues. "Development is a collaborative effort, and I am here to ensure that the needs of Gadwal are met with the urgency they deserve," he stated.

Sarita Tirupatiah, speaking on behalf of the delegation, expressed gratitude for the Chief Minister's receptive approach. "We are confident that under your leadership, Gadwal will witness the much-needed progress and development. Our people have great expectations, and we are here to advocate for their needs," she said.

The meeting concluded on a hopeful note, with promises of follow-up actions and continued dialogue. The delegation left the Secretariat with renewed optimism, ready to work hand in hand with the state government to transform Gadwal into a thriving, well-developed region.

This visit marked a significant step in the ongoing efforts of the Congress party leaders to advocate for their constituency. As they returned to Gadwal, the people awaited the positive changes that were set in motion by their leaders' proactive engagement with the Chief Minister.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/07/12/1461563-revanth.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/zp-ex-chair-persons-pittetion-for-development-of-gadwal-891305</link></article><article><title>Man pours hot oil on hotel owner after dispute over fritters in Gadwal</title><authors>Newstap Bureau</authors><publish_date>2024-09-30</publish_date><text>GADWAL: A man threw hot oil on the hotel owner and another bystander, causing severe injuries, following a dispute over fritters in Guvvaladinne village of KT Doddi mandal of Gadwal district.

According to Sub-Inspector Srinivas, the accused, Vinod, approached a local hotel run by Bujjanna Goud and demanded fritters. When Bujjanna Goud refused, a heated argument ensued between the two. In anger, Vinod threw hot oil on Bujjanna Goud, which also splashed on Veeresh, who was nearby. Both men suffered injuries from the incident.

Following the attack, Veeresh's wife, Shankaramma, filed a police complaint. SI Srinivas confirmed that a case has been registered and that an investigation is underway to address the matter appropriately.</text><top_image>https://www.newstap.in/h-upload/2024/09/30/1656929-man-pours-hot-oil-on-hotel-owner.gif</top_image><link>https://www.newstap.in/crime/man-pours-hot-oil-on-hotel-owner-after-dispute-over-fritters-in-gadwal-1553125</link></article><article><title>Assistant engineer in Gadwal held for taking bribe</title><authors>News Desk</authors><publish_date>2024-11-18</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: An assistant engineer in the panchayat raj department at Itikyal Mandal, Gadwal, Pandu Ranga Rao was arrested by the Anti-Corruption Bureau (ACB) for allegedly demanding and accepting a bribe of Rs. 50,000.

The accused allegedly asked the complainant for the bribe in exchange for processing the measurement book and forwarding the bill for minority community hall work.

The bribe amount was recovered from the accused and chemical tests on his fingers and pocket confirmed the presence of the money.

The accused was produced before the Special ACB Court in Nampally and remanded to judicial custody.

Citizens can report any instances of bribery in Telangana at the toll-free hotline 1064.

On November 14, the Telangana Anti-Corruption Bureau (ACB) arrested the sub-inspector and the police writer of Lingampet police station in Kamareddy district.

The arrested police officers are Lingampet sub-inspector Pabba Arun and constable cum police writer Thota Rama Swamy. They were found taking a bribe amount of Rs 10,000 by the officials, with the chemical test for bribe money turning positive.

In a similar incident of corruption by Telangana police officers, On November 8, the SI of Varni police station in Nizamabad district was arrested by the Telangana ACB officers.

Sub-inspector Krishna Kumar was arrested for accepting a bribe of Rs 20,000 in exchange for granting station bail to an individual arrested for physical assault.

According to officials from the ACB, the complainant, Nagaraju, a farmer, was arrested by the Varni police on November 4 for his involvement in a physical fight, to grant bail for which the officer demanded a bribe and was later nabbed.</text><top_image>https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Tamreen-25.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.siasat.com/assistant-engineer-in-gadwal-held-for-demanding-accepting-bribe-3133623/</link></article><article><title>Gadwal MLA Returns to BRS After Brief Stint in Congress</title><authors /><publish_date>2024-07-30</publish_date><text>In a surprising turn of events, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy has rejoined the Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) party today, less than a month after switching to Congress.

On July 6, 2024, Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy had joined the Congress party in the presence of Chief Minister Revanth Reddy. He was part of a group of former BRS MLAs who made the switch, including Yadaiah (Chevella), Pocharam Srinivas Reddy (Banswada), Sanjay Kumar (Jagtial), Danam Nagendra (Khairatabad), Kadiyan Srihari (Station Ghanpur), and Tellan Venkat Rao (Bhadrachalam).

However, in a significant development, Krishna Mohan Reddy has now returned to the BRS fold. He met with BRS working president KTR and other party leaders on the assembly premises. Sources suggest that Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy was unhappy in the Congress party and had requested KTR to allow him to rejoin BRS.

KTR accepted Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy’s proposal, welcoming him back into the party. BRS leaders are now hopeful that other former party members who recently joined Congress might follow suit and return to the BRS in the near future.

-Sanyogita</text><top_image>https://cdn.telugu360.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/MLA-rejoining-BRS.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.telugu360.com/gadwal-mla-returns-to-brs-after-brief-stint-in-congress/</link></article><article><title>Telangana: New Bharosa centres opened in Mahabubnagar, Gadwal</title><authors>News Desk</authors><publish_date>2024-11-12</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: The Telangana Police Women Safety Wing opened new Bharosa centres on Tuesday, November 12, with a new centre being inaugurated in Mahabubnagar district and an already existing centre moving into a newly built independent building in Jogulamba Gadwal district.

Bharosa centres are operated by the women’s safety department of the police to assist survivors of rape and sexual abuse. The centres provide medical treatment and checkups, counselling, and support to the survivors in filing complaints and also provide the necessities for the rehabilitation of the victims.

The Bharosa centres that provide medical, legal, and mental aid to women and children to overcome the trauma of sexual abuse and rape were inaugurated in 14 districts in the first half of 2024. The new centres were opened in Jagityal, Bhadradri Kothagudem, Jangaon, Mancheriyal, Mulugu, Nagarkurnool, Peddpally, Jayashanker Bhupalpally, Kamareddy, Rajanna, Sircilla, Kumarambheem Asifabad, Narayanpet, Nirmal and Wanaparthy districts.

The initiative was first set up with one centre in Hyderabad in 2016, and upon the pilot project’s overwhelming success, it was widened step by step, and now has expanded into 27 centres across the state.

According to the police, since its establishment in 2016, the Bharosa project has helped 5852 victims related to Protection of Children from Sexual Offenses (POCSO) and 1447 adult rape victims.

The permanent state-of-the-art buildings have been constructed and made operational through the

CSR funding received from MEIL.

Each centre is staffed with professionals including counsellors, psychologists, legal officers, and medical personnel, ensuring comprehensive care.

Also Read Hyderabad police busts international human trafficking ring, rescue 3 women

Work at Bharosa centres and support survivors

Telangana’s Bharosa centres are currently hiring for female-only positions including support persons, legal counsellors, complaints processing executives, health workers, counsellors, psychologists, help desk executives, receptionists, data entry operators, accountants, Bharosa centre coordinators, and more.

There are no application fees. Interested candidates can apply via the Bharosa Centre’s official website.</text><top_image>https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bharosa-Centre-in-Telangana.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.siasat.com/telangana-new-bharosa-centres-opened-in-mahabubnagar-gadwal-3130439/</link></article><article><title>BRS continues to leak MLAs, seventh party leader joins Congress in Telangana</title><authors>Sreenivas Janyala, Cdata, Var Template_Content, Sso_Login_Box, Xwelcome Backorenter The Email Address Or Mobile Number Associated With Your Account To Sign In. Show Passwordsign Innew To The Indian Express Signupxcreate Your Account It Is Quick, Easy.Or Show Passwordnextvalidate Otpregisteralready Have An Account, Signin, Sso_Social_Box, Sign In Withgmailfacebookapple, Var Follow_Widget_Data</authors><publish_date>2024-07-06</publish_date><text>In another setback to the Bharat Rashtra Samiti (BRS) in Telangana, the party’s MLA from Gadwal, Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy, joined the ruling Congress on Saturday.

He is the seventh BRS MLA to join the Congress after the party came to power in November last year. Krishna Mohan Reddy joined the Congress in the presence of Chief Minister A Revanth Reddy, who is also the Telangana Pradesh Congress Committee president. In the Assembly elections held last year, the BRS had won 39 of 119 seats, while the Congress won 64. It rose to 65 after BRS MLA from Secunderabad Cantonment, G Lasya Nanditha, died in a road accident on February 23, and the Congress won the bypoll.</text><top_image>https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/07/Reddy.jpg</top_image><link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/brs-mla-joins-congress-telangana-bandla-krishna-mohan-reddy-9437115/</link></article><article><title>Telangana: Gadwal MLA rejoins BRS from Congress in less than a month</title><authors>News Desk</authors><publish_date>2024-07-30</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: In a major political development, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy who had recently joined Congress jumped back to Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) here on Tuesday, July 30.

On July 6, Reddy had joined the Congress in the presence of chief minister Revanth Reddy. On Tuesday, he met BRS working president KT Rama Rao (KTR) and expressed his desire to join back the party.

It is believed that Reddy’s joining did not go well with some Congress party workers. A few of them protested and raised slogans against Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy in front of Gandhi Bhavan.

It should be noted that Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy defeated Congress leader Saritha Tirupathaiah in the 2023 Assembly elections by a narrow margin of 7,036 votes.

Reddy, who was close to the KTR, had won the combined Mahbubnagar district in the 2023 Assembly elections. Known for his hard work, it is believed that KTR has immense faith in him.

BRS leader Krishank K took a jibe at the chief minister who is currently in USA. Taking to X he said, “Very unfair on your part @KTRBRS, Do you think Mr.Revanth Reddy will have a peaceful holiday to America now He may be worried by the time he returns how many defected MLA’s would leave Congress to join back BRS.”</text><top_image>https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Untitled-design-2024-07-30T135203.109.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.siasat.com/telangana-gadwal-mla-rejoins-brs-from-congress-in-less-than-a-month-3070528/</link></article><article><title>Gadwal BRS MLA Jumps Into Congress</title><authors>Satya B</authors><publish_date>2024-07-06</publish_date><text>BRS is facing back to back jolts from own party members. After a defeat in Assembly elections and another humiliating defeat in Parliament elections, BRS is finding it tough to hold its elected representatives. The Congress is already poaching their MLAs and MLCs. The latest to switch loyalties from BRS to Congress is Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy.

On Saturday, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy joined the Congress party in the presence of Telangana chief minister A. Revanth Reddy and All India Congress Committee (AICC) in-charge of Telangana Deepa Das Munshi.

The total number of MLAs who joined Congress from BRS has now become seven. BRS currently has 31 MLAs.

Earlier, Yadaiah (Chevella), Pocharam Srinivas Reddy (Banswada), Sanjay Kumar (Jagtial), Danam Nagender ( Khairatabad), Kadiam Srihari (Station Ghanpur), and Tellam Venkat Rao (Bhadrachalam) had joined the Congress.

Very recently, 6 MLCs also joined Congress from BRS.

Related

Tags BRS MLA

Youtube Shorts ❮ ❯</text><top_image>https://cdn.gulte.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/BRS-MLA.jpeg</top_image><link>https://www.gulte.com/political-news/302851/gadwal-brs-mla-jumps-into-congress</link></article><article><title>Hans impact: DC inspected the PACS and pesticides shop in Gadwal</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-05-31</publish_date><text>Gadwal: The District Collector BM Santhosh along with the district Agriculture officials inspected the PACS centre and a pesticides Shop.

On Friday, the District Collector BM Santhosh conducted a surprise inspection at the office of the Primary Agricultural Cooperative Society (PACS) in Gadwal. During this visit, he emphasized the importance of ensuring that seeds and fertilizers are sold at subsidized rates to farmers who have received authorization from Agricultural Extension Officers (AEOs), according to the established rules. He stressed that farmers should not be forced to purchase from private dealers at higher prices.

In response, Gadwal PACS Secretary Venkateswara Reddy assured that Telangana State Seeds, the National Seeds Corporation, and Haka are providing the necessary seeds and fertilizers. He added that the required supplies will be available to farmers within the next 15 days.

It was checked whether all the details were entered as per the rules. The District Collector emphasized that not only the officials but also the dealers have the responsibility to ensure that farmers do not suffer due to fake seeds.

District Agriculture Officer Govindu Naik, Assistant Director of Agriculture Department Sangeet Lakshmi, and others participated in the inspection.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/05/31/1451007-bm-santhosh.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/hans-impact-dc-inspected-the-pacs-and-pesticides-shop-in-gadwal-882088</link></article><article><title>Dangers of Consuming Adulterated Toddy in Gadwal district.</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-07-30</publish_date><text>Gadwal : The recent spotlight on adulterated toddy (a traditional alcoholic beverage made from the sap of palm trees) has raised significant health concerns among the residents of Gadwal. Health experts warn that consuming adulterated toddy poses several serious health risks due to the presence of harmful additives and contaminants.





Health Risks Identified :-



Common side effects reported include:

Nausea and Vomiting : The presence of adulterants can severely irritate the stomach lining, leading to frequent bouts of nausea and vomiting.

Diarrhea : Contaminants found in adulterated toddy can disrupt the digestive system, causing persistent diarrhea.

Abdominal Pain : Consumers often experience severe stomach cramps due to harmful substances in the toddy.

Headaches : Chemicals used in the adulteration process can lead to debilitating headaches.

Dizziness and Confusion : Certain substances in adulterated toddy affect the nervous system, resulting in dizziness and confusion.

Respiratory Issues : Some chemicals used in adulteration can cause significant breathing difficulties.

Liver Damage : Long-term consumption of adulterated toddy is associated with liver toxicity and potential liver damage.

Neurological Effects : Harmful chemicals can lead to neurological symptoms such as tremors, seizures, and other severe effects.

Cardiovascular Problems : Adulterants can impact heart rate and blood pressure, potentially causing serious cardiovascular issues.

Allergic Reactions : Unknown substances in the toddy can trigger allergic reactions, ranging from mild skin rashes to severe anaphylaxis.

Severe Consequences



In extreme cases, highly adulterated toddy can lead to organ failure or even death. Health authorities stress the importance of seeking immediate medical attention if severe symptoms are experienced after consuming toddy.



Government Response:



In response to these alarming developments, District SP Mr. T. Srinivas Rao, IPS, has issued strict directives to the Excise and Police officials to ensure that licensed kallu (toddy) shops in the district are free from adulteration. The SP has mandated thorough investigations and severe punishment for those responsible for selling adulterated toddy.



Mr. Rao emphasized the need for regular checks and inspections in kallu shops and depots. He instructed officials to collect samples from suspicious establishments for lab testing and to take stringent action against those found guilty of adulteration. Additionally, unauthorized kallu shops are to be closely monitored to prevent their operation.



Coordination Efforts:

A coordination meeting was held in the SP’s chamber with police and excise officials to discuss the measures to be taken. During the meeting, Excise officials provided details about licensed kallu shops in Gadwal and Alampur constituencies, highlighting potential areas for adulteration.

Community Impact :



The community, particularly laborers and daily wage workers, who are the primary consumers of toddy, are most affected by this issue. The high cost of medical treatments for those affected by adulterated toddy exacerbates the problem, placing a heavy burden on already vulnerable populations.

</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/07/30/1466738-untitled-1.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/dangers-of-consuming-adulterated-toddy-in-gadwal-district-895699</link></article><article><title>Impact of Heavy Rains on Alampur Constituency, Jogulamba Gadwal District</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-08-20</publish_date><text>Gadwal: The heavy rains that occurred in the early hours of Tuesday in the Alampur constituency of Jogulamba Gadwal district have brought to light several critical issues related to infrastructure, disaster preparedness, and the socio-economic impact on the local population. The event underscores the vulnerability of the region to extreme weather conditions and the cascading effects on daily life, transportation, and agriculture.

Infrastructure Vulnerability:

The flooding of the main road connecting Raichur in Karnataka to Alampur due to the overflow of the Pedda Vagu stream highlights the inadequate infrastructure resilience in the region. The fact that a major transportation route was rendered unusable for several hours points to the need for improved drainage systems and the construction of flood-resistant infrastructure. This road serves as a crucial link for both people and goods between the states, and its disruption not only isolates communities but also hampers economic activities.

Disruption of Daily Life:

The flooding led to the isolation of several villages, including Tupatrala, Medikonda, Pulikal, Chinna Tandrapadu, Venisompuram, and Keshavaram. Residents in these areas found themselves stranded, unable to access essential services or travel to work. This kind of disruption can have lasting effects, especially for daily wage laborers and small businesses that rely on consistent access to markets and customers.

The temporary isolation of these villages also raises concerns about the availability of emergency services. In situations where medical emergencies or other critical needs arise, the lack of accessible roads can turn a manageable situation into a life-threatening one. The local authorities' warnings to avoid travel were a necessary precaution, but they also highlight the lack of alternative routes or transportation options in times of crisis.

Agricultural Impact:

Perhaps one of the most significant impacts of the heavy rains is on agriculture, which is the primary livelihood for many residents in the Alampur constituency. The flooding of fields, particularly during the crop-growing season, can have devastating effects. Farmers have reported that their crops, which were in the growth phase, have been submerged by the sudden influx of water. This has led to an estimated loss of up to ₹40,000 per acre, a significant financial hit for small and marginal farmers.

The timing of the rains, when crops are particularly vulnerable, exacerbates the situation. Continuous heavy rains can lead to waterlogging, which damages the roots of crops and reduces yield. For many farmers, this could mean not just a loss of income but also a potential shortage of food supplies in the coming months.

Education and Public Safety:

In the aftermath of the rains, there have been calls from parents in the affected villages for the closure of schools in areas where streams and rivulets have overflowed. This concern is valid, given the risks associated with children traveling through flooded areas. The disruption of education, even temporarily, can have a cumulative effect, especially in rural areas where access to quality education is already limited.

Public safety remains a critical issue. The lack of real-time information about which areas are most affected by flooding means that residents are often left to navigate dangerous conditions with little guidance. This underscores the need for improved communication strategies, including the use of social media and local media outlets, to keep the public informed during such events.

Need for Proactive Measures:

The recurring nature of such weather events calls for more proactive measures from both local and state governments. While immediate responses like warnings and advisories are crucial, long-term solutions are needed to mitigate the impact of heavy rains on the region. These could include the construction of better drainage systems, flood barriers, and the elevation of key roads and bridges.

Additionally, there should be a focus on disaster preparedness training for local communities, ensuring that residents know how to respond in the event of sudden flooding. Investment in early warning systems that can predict and communicate the risks of flooding before they occur would also be beneficial.

The heavy rains in the Alampur constituency are a reminder of the ongoing challenges faced by rural areas in dealing with extreme weather. The disruption of transportation, the isolation of communities, the damage to crops, and the impact on education all highlight the need for a comprehensive approach to disaster management and infrastructure development. By addressing these issues, the region can become more resilient to future weather events, ensuring that the livelihoods and safety of its residents are better protected.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/08/20/1473018-r.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/impact-of-heavy-rains-on-alampur-constituency-jogulamba-gadwal-district-900997</link></article><article><title>Grand Independence Day Celebrations Held in Gadwal.Special Government Representative AP Jitender Reddy Unfurls the National Flag</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-08-15</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Jogulamba Gadwal District witnessed grand celebrations on Thursday, August 15, 2024, as the 78th Independence Day was observed with great fervor at the Police Parade Grounds. The day-long event, marked by a festive atmosphere, saw extensive arrangements made by the district administration to ensure a successful celebration.

The chief guest for the occasion was AP Jitender Reddy, the Special Government Representative and Advisor to the Government (Sports Affairs). He unfurled the tricolor and received a ceremonial guard of honor from the police force. Following the flag hoisting, Reddy extended his Independence Day greetings to prominent citizens, officials, and the general public.

In his address, Jitender Reddy highlighted the various initiatives and developmental programs undertaken by the state government in the district. He emphasized the government’s commitment to resolving public issues and fulfilling its promises swiftly, noting that several welfare programs were initiated within 48 hours of assuming power. He mentioned the ongoing Indiramma Gram Sabhas, which are being conducted to collect applications from the public and implement various schemes effectively.

Reddy announced several key benefits under different government schemes, including free travel facilities for women and transgender individuals in RTC buses. He revealed that this initiative has benefitted over 8.63 million women in the Jogulamba Gadwal district, with a subsidy totaling Rs. 30.68 crores. Under the Rajiv Aarogyasri scheme, the medical coverage limit has been increased to Rs. 5 to 10 lakhs, enabling 3,830 underprivileged individuals in the district to access corporate medical care.

The Indiramma Housing Scheme, aimed at providing a home for every poor family, is being implemented with 4.5 lakh houses under construction across the state, including 3,500 houses in each constituency. Reddy also highlighted the Mahalakshmi Scheme, under which cooking gas is being supplied at a subsidized rate of Rs. 500. So far, 87,751 people in the district have benefitted from this scheme, with 48,683 gas cylinders distributed, amounting to a subsidy of Rs. 1.29 crore.

Additionally, the Grihajyoti program provides free electricity to consumers using up to 200 units, with 140,440 zero bills issued in the district, benefiting 76,358 families. The government has provided a subsidy of Rs. 3.67 crore under this program. Reddy also pointed out the state government’s historic achievement in waiving farm loans up to Rs. 2 lakh, which has benefited 41,638 farmers in the district, amounting to a total loan waiver of Rs. 318.83 crore.

The celebrations also included a series of cultural performances by students from various schools, which captivated the audience. Bal Bhavan students performed a patriotic dance, while the KGBV Undavelli girls presented a striking pyramid display. The SR Vidyaniketan students showcased martial arts, and the KGBV Gadwal girls performed a dance highlighting the importance of trees. Pragnya Vidyalaya students also delivered a performance filled with patriotic fervor.

In recognition of their exemplary services, awards were presented to officials from various government departments. Later, Reddy, along with other officials, visited stalls set up by different government departments. The district welfare department distributed three electronic tricycles and nine regular tricycles to differently-abled individuals.

*District Collector BM Santosh Unveils Schemes at IDOC*

Earlier in the day, District Collector BM Santosh hoisted the national flag at the Integrated District Offices Complex (IDOC) and paid rich tributes to the freedom fighters.

The Independence Day event was graced by the presence of Nagar Kurnool MP Mallu Ravi, District SP Srinivas Rao, Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy, Alampur MLA Vijayudu, Additional Collectors Narsinga Rao and Srinivas Rao, RDO Ram Chander, AO Veerabhadrappa, Additional SP Guna Shekhar, and various district officials, local public representatives, and students.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/08/15/1471587-bm.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/grand-independence-day-celebrations-held-in-gadwalspecial-government-representative-ap-jitender-reddy-unfurls-the-national-flag-899858</link></article><article><title>Jurala project in Gadwal overflows, 17 gates lifted to release excess water</title><authors>Pavan Bandari</authors><publish_date>2024-07-21</publish_date><text>Telangana has been experiencing heavy rainfall for the past two days, leading to flooding in various parts of the state. The Krishna and Godavari rivers are overflowing due to the excessive rains in the upper areas and river basins. The Jurala dam in Gadwal district is also facing flooding as a result of heavy rains in upstream Karnataka.

Currently, the Jurala dam is receiving a flood flow of 92,000 cusecs, leading officials to open 17 gates of the project and release a flood of 67,000 cusecs downstream. Additionally, 33,000 cusecs of water is being released downstream through power generation. The water level in the dam has reached 317.17 meters, close to its full capacity of 318.516 meters.

Furthermore, approximately one lakh cusecs of floodwater from Jurala is expected to reach the Srisailam reservoir. Officials are concerned that the flood could worsen if the rains persist. Meanwhile, the Sriramsagar reservoir is also experiencing a continuous flow of floodwater.

The state government is closely monitoring the situation and taking necessary steps to manage the flooding in the affected areas.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/07/21/1464214-jurala.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/jurala-project-in-gadwal-overflows-17-gates-lifted-to-release-excess-water-893555</link></article><article><title>Gadwal: Farmers protest for relief in Aija</title><authors>The Hans India</authors><publish_date>2024-10-21</publish_date><text>Gadwal: In response to a call given BRS working president KTR, farmers in Aija tried to burn an effigy of Chief Minister A Revanth Reddy. However, the bid was foiled at the petrol station junction in Aija.

Leading the BRS protest, G Chinna Devanna, the municipal chairman, accused the Revanth Reddy government of going back on electoral promises and leaving farmers in the lurch. He demanded immediate release of Rythu Bharosa aid. Councilors Hussein, Venkatesh, Anjaneyulu, and others including former Sarpanch Mahesh, took part in the protest.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/21/1490763-farmers.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/gadwal-farmers-protest-for-relief-in-aija-915864</link></article><article><title>BRS Rajya Sabha member K Keshava Rao, Hyderabad Mayor Gadwal Vijayalaxmi set to join Congress</title><authors>Raj Rayasam</authors><publish_date>2024-03-28</publish_date><text>Rumours of GHMC Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi joining the Congress have been doing the rounds ever since she met Chief Minister A Revanth Reddy on 3 February. (X)

BRS Parliamentary Party leader K Keshava Rao and his mayor-daughter Gadwal Vijayalaxmi will join the Congress soon.

While it is not known when Keshava Rao will jump ship, Vijayalaxmi is expected to join the Congress on 30 March in the presence of Telangana Chief Minister A Revanth Reddy.

Their decision should be a very rude jolt to the BRS, which has been struggling in the political bullring as its leaders leave one after the other in a metronymic rhythm.

The die had been cast for Keshava Rao and his daughter to return to Congress when the national party’s Telangana in-charge Deepa Dasmunsi and chief minister’s advisor Vem Narender Reddy called on them at his Banjara Hills residence on 12 March and invited them to join the grand old party.

The veteran leader and former minister was the president of the Pradesh Congress Committee in the undivided state of Andhra Pradesh.

Keshava Rao’s decision

Keshava Rao announced the decision to leave the BRS and join the grand old party after a meeting with BRS supremo K Chandrashekar Rao on Thursday, 28 March.

A heated discussion is understood to have taken place when Keshava Rao told KCR that he had made up his mind to return to the Congress.

When Keshva Rao was trying to explain his reasons, KCR reportedly interrupted, asking him to spare him the talk.

KCR demanded to know why he was leaving when the party had made him a Rajya Sabha member twice, made his daughter the Hyderabad mayor, and given him a good position in the party.

Cut to the quick, Keshava Rao is understood to have left the meeting in a huff.

After the meeting, Keshava Rao said that he had decided to leave the BRS as he was pining for the days he had spent in the Congress.

“At the age of 80, I am longing to be back in the Congress,” he said, pointing out that he had spent most of his political life in the national party.

“I have very high regard for KCR. He treated me with respect. I discussed Kavitha’s arrest with KCR and felt that she had been framed in the case,” he said.

After the Congress began losing sheen, K Chandrashekar Rao — leading what was then the TRS — took over the leadership of the Telangana movement.

That was when Keshava Rao joined the pink party — in 2013. He was a Rajya Sabha member from the Congress back then.

After the creation of Telangana in 2014, KCR sent him to the Rajya Sabha afresh, and again in 2020.

He was made secretary general of the BRS and the parliamentary party leader. He has been its voice and identity in Delhi for the last 10 years.

First doubts over whether everything was alright in the BRS camp emerged when the ED arrested Kavitha at her residence on 15 March for her suspected involvement in the Delhi liquor scam.

When the legions of the party came out in support of Kavitha, Keshava Rao was nowhere to be seen — either in Hyderabad or in Delhi.

When BRS MPs attended a press conference after her arrest, Keshava Rao was conspicuous by his absence.

Also Read: Substantial BRS bond receipts redeemed at the altar of favour exchange

Siblings differ

According to sources, Vijayalaxmi is expected to don the Congress robes along with her father and 10 trusted corporators.

Vijayalaxmi later told reporters that she had decided to move to the Congress along with her father since it was always better to be in the ruling party, as it would become easy to get works done for Hyderabad city.

Keshava Rao’s son Viplav Kumar, however, differed from his father and sister.

He said he had decided to stay with the BRS and support KCR, and that he had nothing to do with their decision to quit the pink party and join the Congress.

According to sources, Revanth Reddy reached out to Keshava Rao and his daughter to smite a blow to the BRS in Hyderabad, where the Congress did not fare well in last year’s Assembly election.

If Keshava Rao and his daughter were on the Congress’ side, it might become easy for the chief minister to improve the party’s footprint in Lok Sabha constituencies spread across GHMC limits.

He has managed to onboard several city leaders. The BRS’ Khairtabad MLA Danam Nagender also joined the party recently, and he is now its candidate for the Secunderabad Lok Sabha seat.</text><top_image>https://s3.ap-south-1.amazonaws.com/media.thesouthfirst.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/GHMC-Mayor-Gadwal-Vijayalaxmi.jpg</top_image><link>https://thesouthfirst.com/telangana/brs-rajya-sabha-member-k-keshava-rao-hyderabad-mayor-gadwal-vijayalaxmi-set-to-join-congress/</link></article><article><title>The Man of Masses, Nagar Doddi Venkat Ramulu Poised For Leadership in Gadwal district</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-07-22</publish_date><text>Gadwal: In a significant political development, Nagar Doddi Venkatramulu, a seasoned leader and stalwart of the BRS party, is making waves among the people of Nadigadda. Venkatramulu, who has a long history of involvement in the Telangana movement, is being whispered about as the next in line for BRS leadership in the Gadwal constituency.

The recent political shift in Gadwal has been noteworthy. MLA Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy, who was elected under the BRS party symbol, has switched allegiance to the Congress party along with his followers. This unexpected move has created a vacuum in the BRS party's leadership in the district, prompting deliberations among the remaining senior leaders about who will take up the mantle.

Among the prominent figures being considered for the leadership role is Nagar Doddi Venkatramulu. Known for his close association with BRS party chief K. Chandrashekar Rao (KCR), Venkatramulu is a respected member of the BRS Politburo. His popularity and influence within the party, especially in the Gadwal constituency, make him a strong contender for the position.

Venkatramulu's political journey is marked by his unwavering commitment to the Telangana movement. He previously contested as a Mahajan Front candidate in 1999 and as a joint candidate for the Congress and TRS parties in 2004, although both attempts ended in defeat. Despite these setbacks, Venkatramulu remained steadfast in his dedication to the cause and became a prominent figure during the Jogulamba Gadwal movement. His accessibility and spirit of activism have left an indelible mark on the people of Nadigadda.

Despite not receiving the party ticket he hoped for in the last assembly elections, Venkatramulu stayed loyal to the BRS leadership. He worked tirelessly for the victory of the party candidates in both the 2018 and 2023 assembly elections. His non-introverted nature and longstanding association with the party bolster his position as a potential leader during the party's time in power.

Adding to his appeal is Venkatramulu's background as a member of the Backward Classes (BC) community, which enhances his popularity over the current MLA, Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy. The people of Gadwala hold Venkatramulu in high regard, seeing him as a key figure who contributed significantly to the Telangana movement. His potential elevation to BRS leadership is seen as a move towards justice and recognition of his years of dedication and service.

As discussions among senior BRS leaders intensify, there is a growing consensus that Venkatramulu might finally be given the reins of leadership in the upcoming 2024 elections. The heart-beating information among the people of Gadwal is that the senior leaders of the BRS party are taking steps towards bringing Venkatramulu into a leadership role that reflects his contributions and loyalty.

With the political landscape in Gadwal evolving rapidly, all eyes are on the BRS party's next steps and Venkatramulu's future role. His leadership could bring renewed vigor and direction to the party, solidifying its position in the district and ensuring continued progress and development for the people of Gadwal.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/07/22/1464475-kcr.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/the-man-of-masses-nagar-doddi-venkat-ramulu-poised-for-brs-leadership-in-gadwal-district-893780</link></article><article><title>One more U-turn by BRS MLA B Krishnamohan Reddy, meets Telangana CM</title><authors>Indo-Asian News Service</authors><publish_date>2024-08-02</publish_date><text>Hyderabad: Taking another U-turn, BRS MLA Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy on Friday met Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy and expressed his desire to continue in the Congress party.

Krishna Mohan Reddy, who had quit Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) and joined the Congress party last month, had called on BRS working president K. T. Rama Rao on Tuesday and announced his return to the BRS.

On Friday, Krishnamohan Reddy along with Excise and Tourism Minister Jupally Krishna Rao met the Chief Minister at his residence. They left together for the Assembly to attend the session.

The MLA’s meeting came with the Chief Minister a day after the Excise Minister met him and convinced him to continue in the ruling party.

Also Read Telangana: Gadwal MLA rejoins BRS from Congress in less than a month

Krishnamohan Reddy represents the Gadwal constituency in the undivided Mahabubnagar district. Both the Chief Minister and Excise Minister also come from the same district.

On Tuesday, the Gadwal MLA met Rama Rao in the Assembly and expressed his wish to return to the BRS.

The MLA was reportedly unhappy over some Congress leaders in the constituency opposing his entry into the party. He also said to have conveyed to the Minister that the government had to take steps for the development of his constituency as he had convinced his supporters that he had joined the Congress for the development of the constituency. Krishna Rao assured the MLA that the government will take steps in this direction.

On July 6, Krishna Mohan Reddy joined the ruling party in the presence of Chief Minister Revanth Reddy.

He is among 10 MLAs of the BRS who have defected to Congress since March.

Former Speaker Pocharam Srinivas Reddy, who is one of the defectors, hosted a dinner on Wednesday. The Chief Minister, a few ministers and defectors had attended the meeting. The defectors were assured a good political future in the ruling party.

BRS had bagged 39 seats in the 119-member Assembly. However, its tally came down to 28 with the defection of 10 MLAs and the defeat at the hands of Congress in the Secunderabad Cantonment Assembly by-election.

The tally of Congress party has gone up to 72.</text><top_image>https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/BRS-MLA-Krishnamohan-reddy.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.siasat.com/one-more-u-turn-by-brs-mla-b-krishnamohan-reddy-meets-telangana-cm-3072368/</link></article><article><title>SP condoles death of woman cop</title><authors>The Hans India</authors><publish_date>2024-09-19</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Jogulamba Gadwal District SP T Srinivas Rao expressed deep condolences over the tragic death of Kumari Sravani (WPC-230), a woman constable serving at KT Doddi Police Station, who passed away in a road accident near Nagarjuna Sagar on Wednesday.

Sravani was diligently performing her reception duties at the police station, Rao noted and expressed his condolences to the bereaved family. He said her death was a great loss the district police force.

He assured the bereaved family that the police department would stand by them and provide all support and assistance to them in this difficult time.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/09/19/1481691-sp.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/sp-condoles-death-of-woman-cop-908086</link></article><article><title>Jogulamba Gadwal hospital has no OBG facilities, refers out 99% cases</title><authors>Dc Correspondent, About The Author</authors><publish_date>2024-08-03</publish_date><text>The hospital had the third-most number of average outpatient cases per doctor per annum at 19,473, after Narayanpet and Utnoor. The hospital saw 93 patients per hour per counter as per the report, the highest of all districts.

Most significantly, the hospital saw 13.24 stillbirths in 2021-22, the highest of all districts and ahead of 2.88 in Medchal.

The report mentioned the absence of dedicated obstetrics and gynaecology (OBG) wards in the hospital. The patients are being accommodated in the female wards as the mother and child health centre is not fully functional. Due to the lack of OBG services, the referral-out rate of the hospital was 99 per cent —almost all cases related to pregnant women and deliveries are referred to other hospitals.

Between 2016 and 2022, two maternal deaths occurred at the hospital but no review was conducted. "No specific response was furnished by the government regarding non-conduct of the maternal death review," the report stated. The hospital had no specialised operation theatres for cardiac, gynaecology and trauma care cases. It also did not have isolation wards for patients with cancer, AIDS, and even for infectious diseases like measles and tuberculosis.

The report observed that the standard operating procedures (SOPs) for patient safety were not available in the district hospitals of Jogulamba Gadwal, Medak, Medchal-Malkajgiri, Narayanpet, Narsampet and Tandur.

The SOPs for disaster management plan for patient safety and monitoring committees were not available in the district hospitals of Jogulamba Gadwal, Medak, Medchal-Malkajgiri, Narayanpet, Narsampet and Yadadri Bhuvanagiri. As a result, the hospitals cannot prepare themselves for unforeseen events, the report stated.





</text><top_image>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2024/08/02/1828388-images8.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/jogulamba-gadwal-hospital-has-no-obg-facilities-refers-out-99-cases-1813993</link></article><article><title>After four-week honeymoon with Telangana Congress, MLA back in BRS</title><authors /><publish_date /><text>HYDERABAD: Less than a month after joining Congress , Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishna Mohan Reddy is back in BRS.He met BRS working president KT Rama Rao in Telangana assembly on Tuesday and expressed his willingness to return to the party.Mohan, one of the 10 MLAs to quit BRS after its loss in Nov 2023 assembly polls, is the first one to return to BRS. There is a strong buzz in BRS circles that two other MLAs, Kale Yadaiah and Gudem Mahipal Reddy, are planning to quit Congress to return to BRS.Amid rumours of "ghar wapsi" of Bhadrachalam MLA Tellam Venkat Rao, who was seen speaking to his former colleagues in BRS chamber in the assembly, sources scotched the speculation. Rao is said to be close to revenue minister Ponguleti Srinivas Reddy.Krishna Mohan’s move is seen as a setback to CM A Revanth Reddy as Gadwal constituency falls in the erstwhileMahabubnagar district, which is CM’s home turf. Krishna Mohan had joined Congress on July 6.Sources said he had decided to return to BRS as district officials and party unit were giving priority to Saritha Tirupathaiah, who unsuccessfully contested on a Congress ticket against Krishna Mohan. Sources said Krishna Mohan brought to the notice of Congress how he was being overlooked.</text><top_image>https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-112147534,width-1070,height-580,imgsize-1171984,resizemode-75,overlay-toi_sw,pt-32,y_pad-40/photo.jpg</top_image><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/hyderabad/4-week-honeymoon-with-cong-ends-gadwal-mla-returns-to-brs/articleshow/112147525.cms</link></article><article><title>BRS Leaders Arrested in Gadwal district, in Protest Against Attack on MLA Kaushik Reddy's Residence</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-09-13</publish_date><text>Gadwal: BRS Leaders Arrested Near Gadwal in Protest Against Attack on MLA Kaushik Reddy's Residence



Several BRS leaders, including Nagar Doddi Venkata Ramulu, Rangu Maddileti, were taken in to custody and sent to Ieeja police station.And TRS student union leader Kuravapallya, was arrested near Mellacheruvu in Gadwal while he was heading to Hyderabad in response to a call by former Minister Harish Rao to protest against the attack on MLA Kaushik Reddy's residence. The leaders were arrested by local police and taken to the town police station.

Additionally, former TRS market yard chairman Patel Vishnuvardhan Reddy was arrested late at night and shifted to the Aija police station, while BRS leader Boss Hanumanthu Naidu was placed under house arrest.

Speaking on the arrests, BRS leader Nagar Doddi Venkata Ramulu criticized the actions of the police, accusing the Revanth Reddy government of turning the administration into a police state. He remarked that under the current Congress government, arrests have become routine, especially targeting opposition leaders, students, and activists. He condemned the actions as an attempt to suppress dissent and stifle a strong opposition, which he argued is essential for the welfare of the people.

Ramulu further accused the ruling party of orchestrating the attack on MLA Kaushik Reddy after he held a press meet criticizing defections. He claimed the attack, allegedly carried out by MLA Arikepudi Gandhi, was a direct response to Reddy’s statements. Ramulu urged the Congress government to focus on solving public issues rather than suppressing opposition voices.

He also condemned the preemptive arrests in Gadwal constituency, stating that such actions were an attack on democratic rights. Ramulu warned that if Chief Minister Revanth Reddy’s government continues with these methods, the people will rise and teach the Congress party a lesson.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/09/13/1479951-brs.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/brs-leaders-arrested-in-gadwal-district-in-protest-against-attack-on-mla-kaushik-reddys-residence-906719</link></article><article><title>Hyderabad Mayor Vijayalakshmi, 10 BRS corporators likely to join Congress tomorrow</title><authors>P Krishnamurthy</authors><publish_date>2024-03-22</publish_date><text>HYDERABAD: In a jolt to the BRS, the Greater Hyderabad Municipal Corporation (GHMC) Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi is likely to join the Congress.

On Friday, Telangana Congress in-charge Deepa Das Munshi and MLA Rohin Reddy met Vijayalakshmi at her residence. Last month, Vijayalakshmi had also met Chief Minister Revanth Reddy at his residence.

Vijayalakshmi said that she would take decision on joining the Congress after speaking to her followers and activists. According to sources, Vijayalakshmi is likely to join Congress on March 23. Along with the mayor, 10 BRS corporators are likely to join the Congress.

After the meeting on Friday, Vijayalakshmi accompanied by Deepa Das Munshi went on to meet the Mayor's father and BRS Rajya Sabha MP Kesava Rao. The MP had been with the Congress before jumping to the BRS in 2014. While Deepa Das Munshi invited Kesava Rao to join the Congress, it is unclear on how Kesava Rao responded.</text><top_image>https://www.newstap.in/h-upload/2022/12/24/1451000-vijayalakshmi.webp</top_image><link>https://www.newstap.in/telangana/hyderabad-mayor-vijayalakshmi-10-brs-corporators-likely-to-join-congress-tomorrow-1527023</link></article><article><title>Congress Victory Rally helds in Gadwal</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-06-20</publish_date><text>Gadwal: The District Congress party leaders have held a victory rally of MP Mallu Ravi from Nagar Kurnool parliament constituency, During his visit to Gadwal constituency, Nagarkurnool Member of Parliament Mallu Ravi addressed the gathering. He criticized the previous government, stating that development was crippled by the corruption of ministers. He also mentioned the ongoing campaign by BRS leaders to mislead the people of Telangana.

ZP Chairperson and Congress party Gadwal in-charge Sarita Thirupathaiah accompanied Mallu Ravi on this occasion. The visit marked Mallu Ravi's first trip to Gadwal constituency following his victory in the parliamentary elections.

On the occasion of his visit, ZP Chairperson and Gadwal Constituency Congress Party in-charge Sarita Thirupatiah, along with Congress Party representatives, senior leaders, and workers, warmly welcomed Member of Parliament Mallu Ravi at the Ananta puram stage in Gadwal town. From there, a victory rally proceeded to Gadwal town. The rally included paying tributes by garlanding the statues of Babu Jagjivan Ram, Ambedkar, Rajiv Gandhi, and YS Rajasekhar Reddy at the district center.

Later, MP Mallu Ravi addressed the gathering at YSR circle near the old bus stand.

During his address, Mallu Ravi criticized the Telangana state administration under the Kalvakuntla family members, stating that the state did not see significant development. He accused the BRS leaders of misleading the people of Telangana and challenged them to prove that they did not violate the promises made during their tenure.

Ravi assured the people that the Congress party is committed to the development of Gadwal constituency. He pledged to work as a servant to the people of Gadwal and focus on its development. Ravi reiterated his promise to adopt Gadwal constituency following his victory in the parliamentary elections and do his utmost for its progress.

Mallu Ravi reaffirmed his commitment to Gadwal constituency, stating that, as promised to in-charge Saritha and the people, he would adopt the area and actively contribute to its development.

ZP Chairperson and Congress party Gadwal constituency in-charge Saritha spoke as well. She emphasized that under the Congress party's rule, Pragati Bhavan would be transformed into Praja Bhavan by CM Revanth Reddy, following the ideals of Jyoti Rao Phule. She criticized the BRS government, accusing its ministers, MLAs, and leaders of amassing wealth illegally under previous schemes.

Saritha called on Congress party leaders to work equally for the welfare of all people and highlighted that the Congress party is implementing six guarantee schemes in the villages of leaders and activists. Currently, the Mahalakshmi scheme provides free bus service for women, the Griha jyoti scheme offers free electricity for homes, and Arogya Shri offers financial assistance up to 10 lakh rupees.

She mentioned that the government is ready to implement the remaining promises, although some have been delayed due to the election code. The party has devised an action plan to prepare for local body elections and counter the efforts of BRS leaders to mislead the public about the government's intentions.

Saritha urged Congress party leaders to actively engage in village-level activities by forming teams. The leaders she mentioned include former ZP chairperson Bandari Bhaskar, former Consumer chairman Gattu Thimmappa, Bandla Chandrasekhar Reddy, TPCC state leaders Ganji pet Shankar, Dharur mandal ZP TC Padma Venkateswara Reddy, Macharla Varalakshmi Venkataswamy Goud, OBC president Nalla Reddy, town president Mohammad Issac, Amaravai Krishna Reddy, Madhusudan Babu, Gattu Satyanarayana, Latti Puram Venkat rami Reddy, Gonu padu Srinivas Goud, Alwal Rajasekhar Reddy, Krishnamurthy, Seshu, Venkatesh Reddy, and Anand Goud. These leaders, along with councillors and ex-councillors, are expected to play active roles in village-level activities and election preparations.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/06/20/1456017-congress.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/congress-victory-rally-helds-in-gadwal-886189</link></article><article><title>Private hospitals stopped their services for three days against the alleged attack on Ananta Hospital</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-06-26</publish_date><text>Gadwal: In protest against attacks on private hospitals, medical services will be suspended for three days in all private hospitals in Gadwal??

Decision of the Association of Doctors of Private Hospitals

It is okay to stop all medical services for three days

Last night in Ananta Hospital, some people attacked the staff and the hospital very badly

A private hospital was shut down for three days in Jogulamba Gadwal district in protest against the attack.

Attacking a private hospital can lead to several legal consequences under Indian law, as such acts are considered serious offenses. The potential legal consequences including, Criminal Charges : Offenders can be charged under various sections of the Indian Penal Code (IPC), including but not limited to:

Section 147 : Rioting.

Section 148n: Rioting, armed with a deadly weapon.

Section 323 : Punishment for voluntarily causing hurt.

Section 324 : Voluntarily causing hurt by dangerous weapons or means.

Section 427 : Mischief causing damage to the amount of fifty rupees.

Section 452 : House-trespass after preparation for hurt, assault, or wrongful restraint.

Damage to Property Act : Under the Prevention of Damage to Public Property Act, 1984, individuals can be penalized for causing damage to public property, which can be extended to private hospital property if deemed necessary.

Hospital Protection Act : Specific states in India have enacted the Hospital Protection Act (e.g., Maharashtra Medicare Service Persons and Medicare Service Institutions (Prevention of Violence and Damage or Loss to Property) Act, 2010). Under these acts:

- The offender can face imprisonment up to 3 years and/or a fine up to ₹50,000.

- The offender is also liable to pay compensation for the damage/loss caused to the property of the hospital.

4. Civil Liability : Hospitals can also file civil suits seeking damages for the destruction of property, loss of revenue, and other consequential losses.

5. Arrest and Detention : Immediate arrest and detention of individuals involved in the attack may occur, followed by legal proceedings.

6. Professional Consequences : Healthcare professionals involved in such acts may face professional consequences, including suspension or cancellation of their medical licenses.

The legal system in India treats attacks on healthcare institutions with utmost seriousness to ensure the safety and security of medical professionals and facilities.

As well as When medical negligence leads to the death of a patient in India, it can result in both criminal and civil consequences for the medical professionals involved. Here are the potential legal outcomes:

Criminal Consequences

1. Criminal Charges : The responsible medical professional(s) can be charged under various sections of the Indian Penal Code (IPC), including:

Section 304A : Causing death by negligence. This section applies when a death occurs due to a rash or negligent act and can result in imprisonment for up to two years, or a fine, or both.

Section 337 : Causing hurt by act endangering life or personal safety of others.

Section 338 : Causing grievous hurt by act endangering life or personal safety of others.

2. Arrest and Detention : The medical professional(s) involved may be arrested and detained, followed by legal proceedings.

Civil Consequences

1. Compensation Claims : The deceased patient's family can file a claim for compensation under the Consumer Protection Act, 2019. If the medical services are found deficient, the responsible medical professional(s) or hospital may be ordered to pay compensation for the loss and suffering caused.

2. Damages for Wrongful Death : The family can also file a suit for damages under the Law of Torts for wrongful death, seeking monetary compensation for the loss of the deceased's support, services, and companionship.

Professional Consequences

1. Disciplinary Actions : The medical professional(s) involved may face disciplinary actions from the Medical Council of India (MCI) or the respective state medical council. This can include suspension or cancellation of their medical license.

2. Reputation Damage : The medical professional(s) and the hospital may suffer significant reputational damage, impacting their practice and patient trust.

Legal Process

1. Filing a Complaint : The aggrieved party can file a complaint with the police, leading to a criminal investigation. Simultaneously, a complaint can be filed with the Consumer Disputes Redressal Commission for compensation claims.

2. Investigation and Trial : A thorough investigation will be conducted to determine if there was medical negligence. If sufficient evidence is found, the case will proceed to trial.

3. Burden of Proof : In criminal cases, the burden of proof is on the prosecution to establish negligence beyond a reasonable doubt. In civil cases, the burden is on the complainant to prove that the standard of care was not met and that this resulted in the patient's death.

Conclusion

Medical negligence leading to the death of a patient is treated with seriousness in India, involving criminal, civil, and professional consequences for the responsible medical professionals. The legal system aims to ensure accountability and justice for the aggrieved parties while upholding the standards of medical practice.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/06/26/1457651-private-hospitals.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/private-hospitals-stopped-their-services-for-three-days-against-the-alleged-attack-on-ananta-hospital-887527</link></article><article><title>Fwd: Great twist in Gadwal politics If MLA join the Congress</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-06-18</publish_date><text>Gadwal: The recent political developments in Gadwal politics, particularly involving MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy, are creating a buzz among locals and political analysts alike. There is speculation about whether Krishna Mohan Reddy is stepping down from BRS party, which some believe could lead to significant changes in the constituency.



Political analysts suggest that true development in the constituency could be better achieved if these rumors are accurate, allowing for new leadership that focuses more on public welfare than party politics. Locals are expressing a strong desire for leaders who prioritize the well-being of the public over party affiliations, indicating a shift in public sentiment towards developmental politics over factionalism.

It's important to keep an eye on these developments to see how they unfold and impact the future of the Gadwal constituency.

Yes, there are reports suggesting that several BRS MLAs and key leaders are considering leaving the party following their disappointing performance in the 2024 MP elections, where they did not secure any of the 17 contested seats. Some members have already left, and more are preparing to depart. There is also speculation about potential changes in the party's leadership positions, including the roles of the BRS party president and working president. These rumors are gaining traction on social media, indicating a possible shift in the party's internal dynamics.

There is widespread speculation that Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy may be changing parties, which has led to discussions about the potential impact on the local political landscape. If he does leave the BRS, it would further the trend of leaders exiting the party, as seen across various constituencies in the state. This exodus is metaphorically described as leaders "getting down from the car," leaving the "pink nest" of the BRS empty.

Political analysts suggest that if Krishna Mohan Reddy joins the Congress party, it could lead to significant development in the Gadwal constituency. They emphasize the importance of prioritizing public welfare over party loyalty and factionalism, advocating for a focus on the constituency's growth and development. This sentiment is resonating with many locals who desire effective leadership that works towards public welfare rather than being entrenched in party politics.

Locals believe that Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy should consider changing parties not for personal gain but for the betterment of the constituency. They emphasize the necessity of being aligned with the ruling party to effectively work towards local development. The decision to change parties should reflect the collective input of BRS party workers who contributed to his victory in the last election, rather than being driven by his own preferences.

Krishna Mohan Reddy, who won the 2019 assembly elections as a BRS party candidate, and Sarita Tirupathaiah, who was elected as the ZP TC from BRS and became the chair person of the Gadwal district, highlight the importance of considering the broader impact on the constituency's progress and welfare.

Initially, both Krishna Mohan Reddy and Sarita Jogulamba worked collaboratively for the district's development, aligning their efforts to please and persuade the party leadership. However, over time, differences emerged between the two. This rift led to speculation that Sarita might switch parties. After making the switch, Sarita began organizing programs in her own style, becoming more accessible to the public and gaining their support.

Despite the challenges, Krishna Mohan Reddy remained with the BRS party. In the last election, both leaders faced a tough contest but managed to secure the people's approval with a narrow majority. Their journey reflects the complex dynamics within the party and the importance of public connection and development-focused initiatives.

An example of this delicate balance is the narrow majority difference observed in past elections. If MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy decides to join the Congress party, the public is hopeful that he and Sarita tirupathaiah can overcome past differences and egos to unite for the party's and constituency's development.

Sarita, who already joined the Congress party, set a precedent by working closely with the community and gaining their trust. If Krishna Mohan Reddy follows suit, the local populace wonders about the impact on leaders from other parties in Gadwal, particularly the BJP and BRS. The hope is that, with both Krishna Mohan Reddy and Sarita in the Congress party, they can avoid the previous conflicts experienced within the BRS and collaborate effectively to advance the constituency's development.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/06/18/1455442-krishna-mohan-reddy.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/fwd-great-twist-in-gadwal-politics-if-mla-join-the-congress-885613</link></article><article><title>After Dumping BRS, GHMC Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi Joins Congress</title><authors>Abp News Bureau</authors><publish_date>2024-03-30</publish_date><text>On Thursday, Keshava Rao met BRS president KCR at his farmhouse and elaborated on his decision to join Congress.

Keshava Rao, after meeting with KCR, expressed his return to the Congress party as a homecoming, likening it to pilgrims returning home after a journey. Having spent over 10 years with TRS (now BRS), he emphasized his longstanding allegiance to Congress, stating he had been with the national party for 53 years previously and asserted his commitment to remain with it.

In June 2013, Keshava Rao joined TRS a year before the formation of Telangana. The politician served twice as a member of Rajya Sabha nominated by BRS chief K Chandrasekhar Rao.

Speaking to Times of India, he said that his daughter will join Congress initially following which he will join the party.

Keshava's son Viplav Kumar, who is with the BRS, said that he would continue in the pink party.</text><top_image>https://feeds.abplive.com/onecms/images/uploaded-images/2024/03/30/d209f4c8f9264bec8f13c2717a4745dc1711781780719240_original.jpg?impolicy=abp_cdn&amp;imwidth=1200</top_image><link>https://news.abplive.com/elections/gadwal-vijayalakshmi-after-dumping-brs-hyderabad-mayor-joins-congress-viplav-kumar-trs-kesava-rao-1675936</link></article><article><title>Taekwondo awards ceremony held in Gadwal</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-07-13</publish_date><text>Gadwal: The Taekwondo Karate Championship Awards Ceremony was held at Brindavan Garden in Jogulamba Gadwal district center on Saturday. The event, organized by the Taekwondo Karate Association, was a grand success with numerous attendees celebrating the achievements of Taekwondo practitioners.

The ceremony was graced by the presence of the Taekwondo Karate Association State General Secretary, Srihari, and State President, Devidas. During the event, Devidas presented black belts and cups to the accomplished Taekwondo players, recognizing their dedication and hard work.

In his speech, Devidas emphasized the importance of learning karate for everyone, particularly for girls, highlighting its value in self-defense. He also praised Srihari for his relentless efforts in promoting karate education in the Jogulamba Gadwal district, acknowledging his significant contributions to the community.

Many speakers took the stage to commend Srihari for his dedication and impact on karate education. The event saw the participation of notable individuals including Device OBS, Anand ,Shekshawali Achari Narayana Goud, Zahiruddin, Krishna Naidu, Prasad, and others, who all contributed to the vibrant atmosphere of the ceremony.

The Taekwondo Karate Championship Awards Ceremony was a celebration of skill, perseverance, and the positive influence of martial arts in the community, marking another milestone in the development of Taekwondo in Jogulamba Gadwal.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/07/13/1462132-awards.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/taekwondo-awards-ceremony-held-in-gadwal-891753</link></article><article><title>BRSV Jogulamba Gadwal District Coordinator Kurava Pallayya Meets BRS Working President K.T. Ramanna, Discusses Key Student Initiatives</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-10-17</publish_date><text>In a meeting with BRS representatives at Telangana Bhavan, BRS party Working President K.T. Ramanna met with Kurava Pallayya, the BRSV (Bharat Rashtra Samithi Vidyarthi) Jogulamba Gadwal District Coordinator.



During this occasion, K.T. Ramanna instructed Pallayya to establish BRSV committees in every college across the Jogulamba Gadwal district. He emphasized the need to expose the Congress government's negligent attitude towards the education system. He urged for a strong fight to ensure that scholarships and fee reimbursements promised by the Congress government are provided to students. Additionally, he called for action to pressurize the government into addressing infrastructure deficiencies in Gurukul schools and ensuring timely rent payments for rented buildings.

Ramanna also highlighted the importance of continuous efforts to empower students in the district and assured that student leaders working for the party would be given due recognition in the future.

On this occasion, Kurava Pallayya introduced the district BRSV student leaders, including Bharat, Maj, Chinna, Rehman, Raju, Ashok, and other team members, to State President Gellu Srinivas Yadav at Telangana Bhavan.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/17/1489877-brsv.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/brsv-jogulamba-gadwal-district-coordinator-kurava-pallayya-meets-brs-working-president-kt-ramanna-discusses-key-student-initiatives-915135</link></article><article><title>Social media buzz about Gdl MLA Bandla to join Congress</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-06-16</publish_date><text>Gadwal: There has been significant buzz on social media about Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy, the MLA from Gadwal in the erstwhile Mahbubnagar district, possibly leaving the Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) to join the Congress party.

This speculation arises amid concerns that BRS has not achieved much in government affairs and police stations, leading to pressure from party leaders and public representatives for Reddy to switch allegiance.

Reddy acknowledged the pressure but stated that no final decision has been made regarding his potential move to the Congress.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/06/16/1454875-bandla-krishnamohan-reddy.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/social-media-buzz-about-gdl-mla-bandla-to-join-congress-885130</link></article><article><title>Uppari Rajasekhar Sagara from Gadwal Selected for All India Inter-University Taekwondo Championship</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-10-31</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Another shining talent has emerged from the Sagara community in Gadwal district. Uppari Rajasekhar Sagara, the son of Uppari Pedda Rangaswamy Sagara from Bingidoddi village, has been selected to represent Osmania University in the upcoming All India Inter-University Taekwondo Championship, which will be held at Guru Nanak University in Amritsar, Punjab, from November 6 to 9.

Rajasekhar will be guided and mentored by coaches Navdeep Sagara and Pradeep Sagara (from Aiza). The President of the Sagara Association in Gadwal district, Uppari Mirapakaya Venkatesh Sagara, along with senior association members, honored Rajasekhar for his accomplishment.

M. Veeresh, one of the association members, expressed his pride in Rajasekhar’s achievement and encouraged the youth from the Sagara community to excel not only in academics but also in self-defense skills like Karate, Kung Fu, and Taekwondo. He motivated them to pursue careers in the country's defense services, including the Police, Military, Air Force, and Navy, and extended his best wishes for their bright future in serving the nation.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/31/1493641-uppari.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/uppari-rajasekhar-sagara-from-gadwal-selected-for-all-india-inter-university-taekwondo-championship-918440</link></article><article><title>CM Cup 2024 Torch Rally Flagged Off in Gadwal: Aiming to Nurture Athletes from Village to International Level</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-10-19</publish_date><text>Gadwal: District Collector B.M. Santosh said that students and youth should excel in sports from the rural level to the international level. On Saturday, District Collector B.M. Santosh, along with SP Thota Srinivasa Rao and Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy, lit the torch for the "CM Cup 2024" at Sangala Park and flagged off a rally. The torch rally, attended by a large number of youth, proceeded from Sangala Park to the Gadwal Collectorate.

Speaking on the occasion, the District Collector mentioned that the torch rally was organized across the state to raise awareness about the CM Cup 2024, with the goal of nurturing athletes from the village level to the world stage. He emphasized the need to identify talent at the village level to ensure athletes from Telangana can participate in competitions like the Olympics. Through the CM Cup program, athletes with good skills from the village, mandal, and district levels will be selected and encouraged to compete at the state, national, and international levels, including the Olympics. The government, in addition to providing special incentives, will also offer government jobs to those who excel in sports. He highlighted the state's recent appointments of athletes like Nikhat Zareen, who participated in the Olympics, and Mohammad Siraj, a T20 World Cup cricket winner, to DSP-level positions. He also noted that sports have evolved from being just games to becoming professional careers. While mental health is important, physical health is equally crucial, and sports play a vital role in personal development. He added that through sports, individuals not only improve physical fitness but also become mentally stronger.

SP Srinivasa Rao remarked that sports improve both physical health and mental strength. He added that individuals excelling in sports have better opportunities to join the police force, as it requires a combination of physical and mental strength to overcome the challenges in the field. He mentioned that the government is fully committed to promoting young athletes selected from the village level through the CM Cup, giving them opportunities to excel at the state and national levels.

Gadwal MLA Krishna Mohan Reddy highlighted that the main objective of the CM Cup 2024 is to identify and encourage talented athletes from villages, mandals, and districts. He assured that every athlete at the mandal, village, and district levels would receive appropriate opportunities. He also expressed his hope that athletes from Gadwal will be selected for state-level competitions, and further, that athletes from the region will participate in the Olympics representing Telangana.

Additional Collector Lakshmi Narayana, Battalion DSP Raghunath Chauhan, District Sports Officer B.S. Anand, officials, and athletes were present at the event.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/10/19/1490459-cm.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/cm-cup-2024-torch-rally-flagged-off-in-gadwal-aiming-to-nurture-athletes-from-village-to-international-level-915619</link></article><article><title>Mayor to dump BRS and shift loyalties to Congress?</title><authors>S Bachan Jeet Singh</authors><publish_date>2024-03-23</publish_date><text>HYDERABAD: The BRS has been experiencing a series of setbacks as MLAs, MPs and MLCs, and prominent leaders are leaving the party and joining either the Congress or BJP.

Facing another jolt on Friday, Hyderabad Mayor Gadwal Vijayalakshmi is likely to shift loyalties to the Congress from the BRS soon. This comes after the state AICC in-charge Deepa Dasmunsi, Advisor to Government Vem Narender Reddy and DCC Khairatabad president Rohin Reddy met the Mayor at her residence and invited her to the Congress party. The mayor said that she would make a decision after discussing with the party and considering their opinions. Additionally, a few more BRS corporators from GHMC are also expected to join Congress.

‘’I will take a decision after consulting my supporters, who have played an important role in my previous two GHMC elections,’’ the Mayor said.

The Mayor had a courtesy meeting with Chief Minister A Revanth Reddy in the first week of February, where she reaffirmed her allegiance to the BRS.

Gadwal Vijayalakshmi, daughter of BRS general secretary and MP K Keshav Rao, contested and won as a corporator of Banjara Hills on behalf of the BRS in 2016 election in the GHMC, and won again in 2020, subsequently being elected as Hyderabad Mayor.

As part of ‘Operation Akarsh’, the Congress is focusing on attracting strong leaders into the party fold from the BRS to bolster its presence in Greater Hyderabad.

Despite not wining any Assembly seat in the Greater Hyderabad limits, which has 24 Assembly constituencies, the grand old party aims to strengthen its position in the city. Already a few BRS corporators defected to the Congress, with more expected to follow suit soon.

After the meeting on Friday, Vijayalaxmi along with Deepa Dasmunsi, met BRS Rajya Sabha MP Kesava Rao. She also invited Kesava Rao to join the Congress. However, his response remains unclear.

A few weeks ago, Deputy Mayor, Mothe Srilatha Reddy with her husband and BRS leader, Sobhan Reddy and former BRS Deputy Mayor, Baba Fasiudding joined the Congress at Gandhi Bhavan.</text><top_image>https://media.assettype.com/newindianexpress%2F2024-03%2F9f4d4ced-067a-44c2-91f2-8b8a0a485259%2FMAYOR.jpg?rect=0%2C110%2C323%2C170&amp;w=1200&amp;ar=40%3A21&amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;ogImage=true&amp;mode=crop&amp;enlarge=true&amp;overlay=false&amp;overlay_position=bottom&amp;overlay_width=100</top_image><link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/states/telangana/2024/Mar/23/mayor-to-dump-brs-and-shift-loyalties-to-congress</link></article><article><title>Teachers’ Day Celebrations Held in Jogulamba Gadwal District</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-09-05</publish_date><text>Gadwal: The role of teachers in shaping the future and development of students is crucial, said District Collector B.M. Santosh during the Teachers' Day celebrations held at the Ananta Functional Hall in the district headquarters on Thursday. The event, organized to honor the birth anniversary of Dr. Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan, saw the felicitation of the district's best teachers.

Collector B.M. Santosh and Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy attended the event as chief guests. The program began with the lighting of the ceremonial lamp. Speaking on the occasion, the District Collector emphasized that teachers play a pivotal role in a student's personality development and future success. He extended special thanks to the teachers of the Gadwal region for their dedicated service. The Collector also highlighted the importance of using modern technology in education and urged every teacher to adopt and mentor at least five students, helping them excel in their studies.

He further noted that a teacher's behavior significantly influences a student's character, and therefore, teachers should not only focus on academics but also encourage physical education. The Collector also announced funds under the Special Development Fund, with ₹60 lakhs allocated to the Government Girls High School, ₹75 lakhs to the Government Girls Junior College, ₹50 lakhs to ZPHS Revalapalli, and ₹30 lakhs to MPPS Bureddipalli.

Gadwal MLA Bandla Krishnamohan Reddy, in his address, stressed the importance of teachers in every field, stating that success in any area requires the support and guidance of teachers. He added that while a mother gives birth to a child, a teacher helps shape their future, and urged the teachers of the district to continue bringing honor to the region through their efforts.

A total of 53 teachers were recognized as the best in the district, with the District Collector, Gadwal MLA, and Additional Collector presenting them with certificates of appreciation, mementos, shawls, and garlands.

The event was attended by Additional Collector Narsinga Rao, Market Yard Chairman Hanumanthu, headmasters, teachers, and students</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/09/05/1477527-teachers.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/teachers-day-celebrations-held-in-jogulamba-gadwal-district-904738</link></article><article><title>MP Mallu Ravi visits Gadwal medical College</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-06-20</publish_date><text>Gadwal: Dr. Mallu Ravi, the Member of Parliament for Nagar Kurnool, has instructed authorities to expedite the construction of the Government Medical College and ensure it is operational within the current academic year. During his visit to Gadwal on Thursday, Dr. Ravi, accompanied by Additional Collector (Local Bodies) Apoorva Chauhan and ZP Chairperson Sarita, inspected the ongoing construction at both the Government Medical College and the District Hospital. He thoroughly reviewed the progress of the construction works and directed officials to take the necessary steps to complete the remaining tasks swiftly to meet the academic deadline.

Dr. Mallu Ravi ordered that Rs. 39 crores have been spent so far on the construction of the medical college. He emphasized the need to send proposals to the government for the additional funds required to complete the remaining work. Steps should be taken to start MBBS first-year classes with 50 students in the academic year 2024-25.

After visiting the local government hospital, he inquired with hospital supervisor Dr. Naveen Kranti about the current medical, paramedical, and other staff working there. Due to the shortage, medical officers, radiologists, and other medical staff are needed at the hospital.

When the medical officials informed MP Dr. Mallu Ravi that they were unable to provide proper services to the patients due to a shortage of staff, he immediately contacted top officials of the medical and health department over the phone. He urged them to take steps to appoint the necessary medical staff. The higher authorities were instructed to ensure that the required medical staff is appointed in all the hospitals in Gadwal, Vanaparthy and Nagar Kurnool segments of the Nagar Kurnool parliamentary constituency.

Dr. Mallu Ravi also suggested that necessary steps be taken to resolve all issues and provide better medical services to the patients in the government hospitals of Achampet, Kalwakurty,and Kolhapur.

During the program, several key figures participated, including:

Medical College Principal Parvathi

T.G. MSI DC Executive Engineer Jaipal Reddy

Miscellaneous officials

Local public representatives

These participants were involved in the inspection and discussions regarding the completion and functioning of the Government Medical College and the local hospital services.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/06/20/1456016-mallu-ravi.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/mp-mallu-ravi-visits-gadwal-medical-college-886188</link></article><article><title>BRSV Jogulamba Gadwal District Coordinator Kurva Pallayya Extends Congratulations to New Alampur Mandal MEO Ramulu Dayal</title><authors>M Veeresh</authors><publish_date>2024-09-26</publish_date><text>Gadwal: At the MRC building in the Alampur constituency’s Ieeja Mandal, BRSV Jogulamba Gadwal District Coordinator, Kurva Pallayya, honored newly appointed Mandal Education Officer (MEO), Ramulu Dayal, by presenting him with a shawl and extending his best wishes.

On this occasion, District Coordinator Kurva Pallayya stated:

He urged the MEO to focus on providing basic amenities and quality education in both private and government schools in Ieeja Mandal. He suggested that private schools be inspected twice a month to ensure the availability of essential facilities, such as toilets, bathrooms, and proper student supervision, to maintain high educational standards.

He also emphasized the importance of ensuring that private school buses are equipped with CCTV cameras, cleaners, GPS tracking, and fitness certifications. In light of recent school bus accidents, Pallayya stressed the need for strict measures to prevent such incidents.</text><top_image>https://assets.thehansindia.com/h-upload/2024/09/26/1483942-brsv.jpg</top_image><link>https://www.thehansindia.com/telangana/brsv-jogulamba-gadwal-district-coordinator-kurva-pallayya-extends-congratulations-to-new-alampur-mandal-meo-ramulu-dayal-910044</link></article><article><title>One killed, 17 injured in lorry-autorickshaw collision in Jogulamba Gadwal</title><authors>Newstap Bureau</authors><publish_date>2024-08-15</publish_date><text>GADWAL: A woman was killed, and 17 others were seriously injured when a lorry collided with an autorickshaw on National Highway 44 in Undavelli Mandal of Jogulamba Gadwal district.

A woman, identified as Lakshmi Devi, was killed on the spot, while 17 others with serious injuries. The condition of three individuals is reported to be critical. The injured were swiftly transported to Kurnool Government Hospital via a 108 highway ambulance.

The victims, female labourers from Tandrapadu village in Kurnool district, Andhra Pradesh, were travelling to Kanchupadu village in Undavelli Mandal for daily agricultural work when the accident took place.</text><top_image>https://www.newstap.in/h-upload/2024/08/15/1646348-one-killed-17-injured-in-lorry-autorickshaw.webp</top_image><link>https://www.newstap.in/crime/one-killed-17-injured-in-lorry-autorickshaw-collision-in-jogulamba-gadwal-1547999</link></article><article><title>Heavy rains disrupt power supply across villages in Gadwal</title><authors>Telangana Today</authors><publish_date>2024-08-20</publish_date><text>Heavy rains disrupt power supply across villages in Gadwal

Farm labourers had a narrow escape when the tractor in which they were travelling got stuck in the canal

By Telangana Today Published Date - 20 August 2024, 02:13 PM

Representational Image

Jogulamba Gadwal: Farm labourers heading to work in the fields had a narrow escape on Tuesday when the tractor in which they were travelling got stuck in the canal.

A few workers boarded a tractor in Utnoor village under Ieeja mandal for work. Soon as the driver tried to move ahead in the canal despite the water flow, the tractor got stuck. As workers raised the alarm, villagers immediately pulled back the tractor using another tractor. All the workers and driver were rescued safely.

Meanwhile, power supply was disrupted in 16 villages across the district after heavy rains coupled with thunderstorms lashed on Monday. Technical snags developed in transmission of power under the Alampur division. The glitches under Shantinagar 33 KV line, disrupted the power supply in 16 villages of Ramapuram, Chaglapur and PT Padu 33/11 substation limits.

There was feeder breakdown and locals raised complaints over the disruption in power supply. The TSSPDCL staff conducted line to line patrolling and fixed the insulators at eight locations and took up pin binding works at two other locations last night and restored the power supply.

TSSPDCL Managing Director Musharaf Faruqui instructed the staff at the field level to be alert and attend to the complaints raised by consumers. He also urged the consumers to lodge complaints of power disruption or any technical issues over 1912 or control rooms at circle or district levels.</text><top_image>https://media.telanganatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/power-supply.jpg</top_image><link>https://telanganatoday.com/heavy-rains-disrupt-power-supply-across-villages-in-gadwal</link></article></articles>